<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guides on CommunityOverCode Asia 2024</title>
    <link>/2024/guide.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guides on CommunityOverCode Asia 2024</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/2024/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Visa Letter Request</title>
      <link>/2024/guide/visa_letter_request.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/guide/visa_letter_request.html</guid>
      <description>For those needing a visa invitation letter, please refer to the instructions on this page
INSTRUCTIONS Before asking for a visa invitation letter, please check out the website of Chinese Visa Application Service Center for the visa application in your city.
Please pay attention to the latest visa policy of China:   144-Hour Visa-Free Transit Policy   China has resumed the 144-hour visa-free transit policy, which allows people from certain countries to enjoy six days of travel to select areas of the country without applying for a visa beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a presentation slide</title>
      <link>/2024/guide/presentation_slides_template.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/guide/presentation_slides_template.html</guid>
      <description>We have a slides template.
We strongly recommend you to use the template, but if you don’t plan to use it for your entire presentation, please use the title slide at least.
 If you use your own template, please set your slide size ratio as 16:9. Do not include any offensive or sexualized references. This would be a violation of the Code of Conduct.  Talks are 30 minutes long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convince Your Boss</title>
      <link>/2024/guide/convince_your_boss.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/guide/convince_your_boss.html</guid>
      <description>Want to attend but not sure how to bring it up with your boss? We’ve created this sample email to help you explain why it’s important to attend CommunityOverCode Asia 2024. Feel free to use the full letter or pieces that work for you. See you in Hangzhou!
Download Template </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessiblity</title>
      <link>/2024/guide/accessibility.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/guide/accessibility.html</guid>
      <description>CommunityOverCode Asia strives to be a welcoming, inclusive, and accessible environment for all, regardless of ability.
Participants requiring special accommodations should provide details in their registration and/or by emailing us at ningjiang@apache.org. This information will be kept private and only be shared with individuals who need to know to secure these accommodations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
