<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CommunityOverCode Asia 2024 will be held in Hangzhou from July 26 to 28，2024 on CommunityOverCode Asia 2024</title>
    <link>/2024/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CommunityOverCode Asia 2024 will be held in Hangzhou from July 26 to 28，2024 on CommunityOverCode Asia 2024</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/2024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Venue &#43; Travel</title>
      <link>/2024/venue_travel/venue.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/venue_travel/venue.html</guid>
      <description>Venue    The Zheda Yuanzheng Forest Hotel, located on the south side of the Yuquan Building (Building A), in the Zhejiang University Forest Park, Hangzhou City, Zhejiang Province, leverages the talent construction and innovation ecosystem resources of Zhejiang University. It is a comprehensive facility that combines conference, hotel, and leisure services. Nestled against the mountains and near water, the center boasts a beautiful environment, making it an ideal location for academic exchanges, seminars, corporate training, and various conferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visa Letter Request</title>
      <link>/2024/guide/visa_letter_request.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/guide/visa_letter_request.html</guid>
      <description>For those needing a visa invitation letter, please refer to the instructions on this page
INSTRUCTIONS Before asking for a visa invitation letter, please check out the website of Chinese Visa Application Service Center for the visa application in your city.
Please pay attention to the latest visa policy of China:   144-Hour Visa-Free Transit Policy   China has resumed the 144-hour visa-free transit policy, which allows people from certain countries to enjoy six days of travel to select areas of the country without applying for a visa beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a presentation slide</title>
      <link>/2024/guide/presentation_slides_template.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/guide/presentation_slides_template.html</guid>
      <description>We have a slides template.
We strongly recommend you to use the template, but if you don’t plan to use it for your entire presentation, please use the title slide at least.
 If you use your own template, please set your slide size ratio as 16:9. Do not include any offensive or sexualized references. This would be a violation of the Code of Conduct.  Talks are 30 minutes long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convince Your Boss</title>
      <link>/2024/guide/convince_your_boss.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/guide/convince_your_boss.html</guid>
      <description>Want to attend but not sure how to bring it up with your boss? We’ve created this sample email to help you explain why it’s important to attend CommunityOverCode Asia 2024. Feel free to use the full letter or pieces that work for you. See you in Hangzhou!
Download Template </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Nifi and Minifi Use cases for IoT</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/iot-1073.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/iot-1073.html</guid>
      <description>Introduce and Reintroduce Apache Nifi and Minifi for various IoT data collection and data routing use cases, with technical deep dives
Speakers: Yan Liu: Cloudera, Cloudera Solution Engineering . Apache Hive and Apache Flink Contributor. Over 10 Years of Practical Experience in Big Data and my current focus is real-time data warehouse using Apache Flink, Apache Hive, and Apache Iceberg. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BanyanDB&#39;s New Column-Based Storage Engine</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1013.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1013.html</guid>
      <description>n this session, I will be introducing BanyanDB&amp;rsquo;s latest column-based storage engine. This advanced technology is designed to be more memory-efficient, requiring less storage and reducing the overhead associated with managing observability data.
Introducing this new engine is a significant breakthrough in our ability to handle large volumes of data effectively and efficiently. We will discuss its design principles, benefits, and the impact it can have on current systems. Furthermore, we will explore its potential applications and the future direction of this technology within the landscape of cloud-native systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lesson Learned from Building an Inner Source Community and an Open Source Community</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1026.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1026.html</guid>
      <description>Building community in the company? I know it sounds hard, but it&amp;rsquo;s also challenging and fun. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my experience of introducing the open-source culture to my company, and the practices of building an inner source or open-source-like community in the company. At the same time, I&amp;rsquo;m also building a real open-source community outside the company (https://codekitchen.community). I&amp;rsquo;ll share the differences and lessons learned from building these two communities, and how to find the connections to empower each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to render in your webapp - a practical guide</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/webserver-1139.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/webserver-1139.html</guid>
      <description>In the olden days it there was little choice about where to render web pages - it all happened on the server. Now there are many choices - server-side, client-side, edge, and various mixtures thereof. Making the wrong choice can be hard to revert and will have negative impacts throughout the lifecycle of a web application.
This talk will present the major approaches for rendering, outline their benefits and trade-offs from a user experience, developer experience, and operational point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache NuttX: The Operating System that Changes the IoT Industry</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/iot-1072.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/iot-1072.html</guid>
      <description>Apache NuttX is a real-time operating system (RTOS) that is characterized by its compliance with standards and small footprint. It can be extended in 8- to 64-bit microcontroller environments and mainly follows Posix and ANSI standards. The overall design, code organization, and compilation process of Apache NuttX are very similar to Linux, which will greatly reduce the migration cost for Android/Linux developers. This presentation will introduce the design principles and main subsystems of Apache NuttX, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitino: A multi-regional, geo-distributed meta datalake</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/incubator-1066.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/incubator-1066.html</guid>
      <description>Welcome to a presentation on Gravitino! Managing metadata can be complex and time-consuming, but Gravitino offers the ultimate solution. It provides a single source of truth for multi-regional data with geo-distributed architecture support. This allows you to store and manage your data in one place, accessible from anywhere globally. With unified data and AI asset management, you get centralized security and data access management, making data protection easier. Gravitino helps you focus more on your data by simplifying tasks and offering these benefits:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Kubernetes network traffic by using eBPF</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1012.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1012.html</guid>
      <description>As more and more applications are deployed in Kubernetes, monitoring network traffic in Kubernetes becomes increasingly important. In this session, I will demonstrate to you how to monitor application network traffic non-intrusively using eBPF technology, covering from L2 to L7 comprehensively.
Speakers: Han Liu: Tetrate, Software Engineer, SkyWalking PMC &amp;amp; Committer, open source enthusiast, focusing on Go, eBPF, and other technology development. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pekko Stream for the win</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/webserver-1138.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/webserver-1138.html</guid>
      <description>What is Pekko and how pekko is been used at taobao
Speakers: Ping He: 技术专家, Pekko PMC and contributors </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The application and technical principles of asynchronous materialized views</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1113.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1113.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction to the application scenarios of asynchronous materialized views Technical principles and current limitations of asynchronous materialized views, including full and incremental construction, transparent rewriting of materialized views, etc Limitations of asynchronous materialized views Future functionalities of asynchronous materialized views  Speakers: Si Wu: Beijing Flywheel Data Technology Co., Ltd. Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province, China.Database Developer, Wu Si is a database optimizer developer with several years of experience in materialized views.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Data Infrastructure in the Age of LLM</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/ai-1006.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/ai-1006.html</guid>
      <description>Data driven by LLMs can make applications more efficient, accurate and personalized, and AI has been widely used in a variety of scenarios, such as natural language processing, recommendation systems and data analysis, and has achieved remarkable results. Big models can better optimize data, and deeply optimized data can better train big models, LLMs and data complement each other.
In this talk, we will introduce how our open source Gravitino builds a unified metadata lake to manage all the metadata of data teams and AI teams with Single Source Of Truth, which not only fills the gap of metadata management of AI models, but also provides clients in Java, Python, and NodeJS, which allows data teams, AI teams, and business teams from different departments to use Gravitino to manage their metadata in a single source of truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winning AI Developer Hearts in Open-Source Community: Innovative Content Marketing Strategy for B2D</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1025.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1025.html</guid>
      <description>In the era of AI 2.0, the emergence of open-source large language models like LlaMa and Mistral are transforming the community and experiences of AI developers, offering unprecedented opportunities and challenges for Business-to-Developer (B2D) operations. As a B2D operator, you might be considering the following questions:
  Are you searching for targeted content marketing strategies that resonate with AI developers, capture their attention, and unleash their potential?
  Have you considered how AI large language model developers differ from traditional developers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Paimon: from Incubator to TLP</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/incubator-1065.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/incubator-1065.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Paimon is a unified datalake format for both batch and streaming processing. Paimon innovatively combines the LSM tree structure in its lake format, enabling the realtime lakehouse architecture within Flink, Spark, Starrocks and more. We will begin with an overview of Apache Paimon, and how Paimon helps our users to build a data infrastructure with both low-latency and high throughput.
Starting as a sub-project from the Apache Flink community, Paimon once had a chance to directly become an Apache top-level project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a time-series database with ASF open source projects</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/iot-1071.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/iot-1071.html</guid>
      <description>The presentation will focus on leveraging the in-memory columnar storage format Apache Arrow, an out-of-the-box query engine Apache Datafusion implemented in Rust, and a universal storage data access layer Apache OpenDAL. By integrating these powerful ASF open-source projects, we built a cloud-native, high-performance, flexible time series database that provides efficient storage and querying support for time series data.
Speakers: Wenkang Xu: GreptimeDB, Engineer, A former Windows Phone App Developer, A second-hand E-bike user, and A New Grads Database Engineer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Governance: A Lawyer&#39;s Practical Guide</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1024.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1024.html</guid>
      <description>Drawing from a robust career in legal practice, specializing in intellectual property law, this presentation will explore open source governance and compliance from a seasoned legal perspective. As a lawyer who has advised a many enterprises, I will share practical insights and proven strategies developed through firsthand experiences. The talk will focus on the intricacies of complying with open source licenses and crafting governance frameworks that are scalable and adaptable to any enterprise size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SeaTunnel Technology Architecture Evolution &amp; Application in AI</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/dataops-1060.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/dataops-1060.html</guid>
      <description>By sharing the evolution of the technical architecture of the SeaTunnel project, we will understand how a data integration tool is built from zero, what core requirements need to be considered, and how to best implement these requirements.
At the same time, we will introduce the application of SeaTunnel in the field of AI to everyone.
Speakers: JUN GAO: ASF Member, Apache SeaTunnel PMC Chair, Apache DolphinScheduler PMC Member, ASF Member, Apache SeaTunnel PMC Chair, Apache DolphinScheduler PMC Member </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sql support in Elasticsearch via Apache Calcite</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1112.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1112.html</guid>
      <description>Elasticsearch has been widely used in ad scenarios. However, in many scenarios, their query patterns are flexible and complex, and their performance requirements cannot be met by ES. To more effectively support complex analytical processing (AP) queries in these scenarios, we have implemented SQL parsing and execution plan construction on the Elasticsearch cluster using the Calcite framework. It supports most common SQL operations and enables efficient Joins. In this presentation, we will delve into how Elasticsearch utilizes Calcite to optimize execution plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The practice of Apache APISIX  in ChinaMobile Cloud</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1011.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1011.html</guid>
      <description>Apache APISIX is a dynamic, real-time, high-performance API gateway. It provides rich traffic management features like dynamic upstream, traffic limit, observability, etc. Also it supports multi protocols like http, grpc, dubbo, mqtt, etc. This presentation introduces the practice of a cloud-native gateway based on Apisix for China Mobile Cloud, including an analysis of the cloud-native gateway architecture, the development of ingress-controller, and how it helps China Mobile NetDisk in handling billions of daily access traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xiaomi&#39;s Practice on Data and AI Fabric Based on Gravitino</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/ai-1005.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/ai-1005.html</guid>
      <description>As the integration of data and AI grows tighter, unified management of both becomes an internal challenge for enterprises. Databricks has introduced a commercial product that bridges big data and AI through the Unity Catalog. However, since it is proprietary, it is difficult for enterprises to implement this solution internally.
In the past few years, Xiaomi has unified the metadata system for table data management, which has brought significant benefits. This year, we have extended the metadata management to the AI data domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero code instrumentation for All-Release Apache Tomcat observability</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/webserver-1137.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/webserver-1137.html</guid>
      <description>With the introduction of JVMT technology, the javaagent-based instrumentation like Apache Skywalking-Java is becoming more and more popular among users. Although javaagent is non-intrusive to the user&amp;rsquo;s code, the corresponding instrumentation code needs to be adapted accordingly when user&amp;rsquo;s code changes. Apache Tomcat, as an active open-source project with a long history, has so many releases, and Apache Tomcat releases quite frequently, which brings a lot of challenges to the development of javaagent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ant Group Open Source Incubation Based on Apache Way</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1023.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1023.html</guid>
      <description>Ant Group (fintech company with 25K employees) has been an active participant in Open Source community with many projects, yet most projects were primarily governed and operated by Ant Group and we don&amp;rsquo;t actively work with OSS Foundations, Apache Foundation included for a long time.
Founding Open Source Program Office (OSPO) and begin properly doing OSS governance has changed that. Now, Ant Group has tailored OSS technical strategy, and comprehensive internal governance process + practices + products to support the strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From an open source novice to streampark committer, my story with apache streampark</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/incubator-1064.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/incubator-1064.html</guid>
      <description>It tells the story of a newbie born in 2003 who participated in open source for the first time. He gradually participated in the apache straempark community, led several major features, and was nominated as a committer. And he joined the new company with his open source contributions and was responsible for the company&amp;rsquo;s internal StreamPark-related development. In this process, I have grown a lot from the community to the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement automatic observability of Tomcat applications under GraalVM static compilation</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/webserver-1136.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/webserver-1136.html</guid>
      <description>GraalVM static compilation has a significant effect on improving Tomcat web application startup speed and runtime memory usage. It is very valuable for it to flourish in Cloud Native ecosystem. However, the automatic instrumentation originally provided based on Java Agent will become invalid after static compilation. Our team designed a static instrumentation solution in GraalVM to solve above problem (https://github.com/oracle/graal/pull/8077). This talk will introduce following two parts:
 The overall design idea of the solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice of Apache DolphinScheduler Api Refactoring  </title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/dataops-1059.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/dataops-1059.html</guid>
      <description>To deliver a session about the practice of DolphinScheduler api refactoring and related task, including
 Why put restful standard into DolphinScheduler Api Api document generation pipeline optimization Api test pipeline optimization  Speakers: Yifan Sun: EMR, Alibaba Cloud, EMR Serverless Spark, EMR Notebook, EMR Workflow, Team leader of EMR Serverless Spark Platform @Alibaba Cloud, also have an ownership on EMR Notebook and EMR Workflow. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RayII.Java--a Java-based new design &amp; implementation of project Ray</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/ai-1004.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/ai-1004.html</guid>
      <description>Project Ray, an open source distributed artificial intelligence framework that have a rapid development in the AI world, is now  about to enter the 3.x development stage. Ray is originally born for high-performance reinforcement learning, while has evolved into a unified computing framework for scaling AI and Python workloads. Ray is also what behind the training of large language models such like ChatGPT. Whether the architecture and implementation of Ray can be further improved/extended to adapt to different hardware and software ecosystems is the main direction of our further research work at present, including various possible reconstructions of Ray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Apache YuniKorn</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1010.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1010.html</guid>
      <description>Apache YuniKorn is a lightweight, universal resource scheduler for running batch workloads in Kubernetes. YuniKorn extends the scheduling capabilities of Kubernetes and supports a wide variety of workloads such as batch processing, data analytics, and machine learning tasks, with robust support for frameworks such as Spark, Flink, and TensorFlow.
YuniKorn 1.0.0 was released in 2022 and contained many major features, e.g. App-aware scheduling, Hierarchy Resource Queues, Gang Scheduling. Since then, the project has continued to grow, and until the latest release, 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Power of IoTDB Stream Processing Engine in Industrial IoT Edge-Cloud Applications</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/iot-1070.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/iot-1070.html</guid>
      <description>In the landscape of the Industrial Internet, time-series data has emerged as a pivotal source of value cutting across various sectors, stemming from devices, sensors, and other terminal points. The onset of the Industrial Internet era heralds a new era characterized by the coordinated interplay of devices, edges, and the cloud: Devices represent the terminal equipment for data collection; edges serve as the controllers at the edge responsible for data aggregation; while the cloud denotes the cloud servers utilized for data processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache GraphAr (incubating): The Origin of the Project and the Journey into the Apache Incubator</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/incubator-1063.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/incubator-1063.html</guid>
      <description>Numerous graph systems, such as Neo4j, Nebula Graph, and Apache HugeGraph, have been developed in recent years. Each of these systems has its own graph data storage format, complicating the exchange of graph data between different systems. The need for a standard data file format for large-scale graph data storage and processing that can be used by diverse existing systems is evident, as it would reduce overhead when various systems work together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Design of Cloud-Native MQTT Based on RocketMQ</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/iot-1069.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/iot-1069.html</guid>
      <description>As the rapid development of smart homes, the industrial internet, and vehicle networking accelerates, the demand for message communication targeting IoT (Internet of Things) devices is experiencing unprecedented growth. Under such circumstances, efficient and reliable messaging standards have become pivotal. The MQTT protocol, widely recognized in the new generation of IoT scenarios, is gradually becoming the industry standard. The MQTT 5.0 protocol, with its superior design, has emerged as a new industry standard in IoT scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Apache APISIX Empowers WebServers</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/webserver-1135.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/webserver-1135.html</guid>
      <description>How Apache APISIX Empowers WebServers Outline:
 Introduction to Apache APISIX How Apache APISIX collaborates with web servers Enhancements Apache APISIX can provide for web servers Typical scenarios in microservices architecture Conclusion  Speakers: Wei Jin: API7 Solution Architect / Apache APISIX PMC / Apache apisix-ingress-controller Founder / Apache Skywalking Committer, API7 Solution Architect / Apache APISIX PMC / Apache apisix-ingress-controller Founder / Apache Skywalking Committer.
Has extensive industry experience. Lead the Apache apisix-ingress-controller project (https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jingdong Algorithm Debug System (StarGazing) Introduction</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/ai-1003.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/ai-1003.html</guid>
      <description>1.Data Cornerstone Of StarGazing Real-time data link construction based on Flink &amp;amp; ClickHouse Quasi-real-time data link construction based on Iceberg &amp;amp; Starrocks
2.Upper Layer Application：Rank Explaination Of Recommended System Trace Link Debug Link User Behavior portrait User portrait &amp;amp;&amp;amp; Item portrait
3.Upper application: Model Explaination Used Algorithm：shapely value、tree shap、IG and so on The application of Model Explaination in Jingdong: Global feature importance and ranking Feature importance comparison of multiple input SKUs Comparison of the feature competitiveness of a single sku under spu/ product word/category</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-level HA of Apache Druid on K8s architecture</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1111.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1111.html</guid>
      <description>Explain in detail how to ensure multi-level high availability from top to bottom in the Apache Druid on K8s architecture, and its large-scale commercial application in Shopee.
Speakers: Benedict Jin: Expert Engineer, Committer and PMC Member of Apache Druid; Shopee Expert Engineer, technical lead of the Druid team; Member of Alibaba Cloud open-source community; Contracted lecturer of &amp;lsquo;Geek Time&amp;rsquo;; Chinese translator of &amp;lsquo;Java Coding Problems&amp;rsquo;, etc. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSPP2020-2024—The Best Open Source Way for University Students in China</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1022.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1022.html</guid>
      <description>Open Source Promotion Plan(OSPP) is a summer program organized by the Institute of Software Chinese Academy of Sciences and long-term supported by the Open Source Software Supply Chain Promotion Plan. It aims to encourage college students to actively participate in the maintenance and development of open source software, promote the vigorous development of open source software communities, and build the open source software supply chain together.We are open enrollment to college students around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Workflow Orchestration with AI</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/dataops-1058.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/dataops-1058.html</guid>
      <description>Topic: Discussing How to Leverage AI in DolphinScheduler for Enhanced Management of Inter-Task Dependencies within Workflows to Ensure More Efficient Data Engineering and Improved Data Quality
Main Content:
  Introduction to Apache DolphinScheduler
 A detailed overview of Apache DolphinScheduler as a distributed, scalable, and visual workflow scheduling open-source system designed for data processing tasks across various environments.    AI-Enhanced Workflow Orchestration Intelligence
 Predictive Scheduling: By utilizing AI to predict task execution times, DolphinScheduler can more intelligently schedule tasks, optimizing resource utilization and minimizing wait times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seata&#39;s Cloud-Native Evolution: A Roadmap from Deployment to Future Possibilities</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1009.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1009.html</guid>
      <description>The evolution from monolithic architecture to microservices, and from standalone databases to distributed database systems, has become an undisputed reality in modern service delivery. Applications are now broken down into multiple independently deployable services, necessitating remote collaboration among services to complete transactions. This shift introduces complexity in distributed transaction management, requiring solutions that are not only efficient but also adaptable to the ever-changing cloud-native environment.
The discussion will include how Seata is stepping into Seata 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dubbo&#39;s gateway - Dubbo Go Pixiu</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/webserver-1134.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/webserver-1134.html</guid>
      <description>Based on the proxy gateway service of dubbo-go, it solves the problem that the external protocol calls the internal Dubbo cluster. At present, it supports HTTP and gRPC
Speakers: Mengchao lv: Alibaba Senior JAVA Engineer, Member of the dubbo community, specializing in RPC &amp;amp; proxies, now working in the Dubbo Go Pixiu community to build the dubbo ecosystem through the Http direct call dubbo clusters and dubbo mesh control plane ability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhance Your Community Engagement with Apache Answer</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1021.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1021.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Answer is an open-source Q&amp;amp;A platform software. It is designed to enhance your community engagement with features you&amp;rsquo;ll need and love.
In this session, we will start with the paths of how we help users find better answers, how we cherish and reward the good deeds, and engage the users in fun ways.
We would also love to share you ideas on how we have the idea of this project, and how you can use Apache Answer for building your next online community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Observability of LLM within the Apache: Based on OTel and Auto Python Probe Injection</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/ai-1002.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/ai-1002.html</guid>
      <description>In the current tech development trends, large models in AI have become a crucial force driving innovation. However, this leads to an increasing demand for observability and monitoring of these models. Within the Apache ecosystem, OpenTelemetry, as an emerging open-source project, provides standardized tools and interfaces for cross-language telemetry data collection and analysis, while the development of automatic probe injection technology further simplifies the integration process of monitoring systems. This topic will delve into how Apache projects and OpenTelemetry can be leveraged, in conjunction with automatic probe injection technology, to build an efficient, flexible, and scalable observability system for AI large models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Stream Processing with Apache StreamPipes and Apache Pulsar</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/iot-1068.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/iot-1068.html</guid>
      <description>Apache StreamPipes is a self-service (Industrial) IoT toolbox to enable non-technical users to connect, analyze and explore IoT data streams With the addition of support for the Pulsar messaging system in Apache StreamPipes version 0.93.0, we gain the ability to combine the user-friendly interface of StreamPipes with the powerful streaming message processing and storage capabilities of Pulsar. This makes it easier to build more intricate and performance-demanding iot stream processing applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meituan&#39;s Journey with Apache Spark and Gluten</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1110.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1110.html</guid>
      <description>The session by Meituan explores their use of Spark with a vectorized engine in their production environment. It covers the identification of current bottlenecks, the rationale behind choosing Gluten as a Spark plugin, the necessity for a vectorized engine, ongoing research in this area, and the tangible cost savings and performance improvements realized in their real-world operations. The presentation offers detailed insights into Meituan&amp;rsquo;s challenges, decision-making process, and the transformative impact of adopting a vectorized engine in their large-scale data processing pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journey from Incubation to First Release: Unveiling the Apache Answer Release Way</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/incubator-1062.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/incubator-1062.html</guid>
      <description>Join me as I share Answer&amp;rsquo;s journey—from the transformative insights gained by participating in open source, through the story-rich donation process to Apache, to the challenging yet rewarding path to our first release. Discover how open source reshaped my understanding, the collaborative efforts behind Answer&amp;rsquo;s integration into the Apache Software Foundation, and the persistence needed to navigate the complexities of launching our initial version. This session is a concise exploration of lessons learned and the unyielding spirit of the open-source community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The practice of Apache Kyuubi &amp; Celeborn &amp; Dolphinscheduler in Cisco</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1008.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1008.html</guid>
      <description> background the practice of Kyuubi(private cloud and public cloud) integration Kyuubi with Dolphinscheduler integration Kyuubi with Celeborn  Speakers: He Zhao: Cisco, Data Engineer, 2019 until now, working in Cisco as Data Engineer Pengqli Li: Cisco, Data engineer, I am engaged in big data development and familiar with big data storage and processing technology. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we need to build a unified metadata layer - Gravitino？</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/dataops-1057.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/dataops-1057.html</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, more and more data are stored in different clouds and systems in different forms, which brings challenges to the enterprise&amp;rsquo;s data governance, security control, and data compliance. The explosion of AI demand has also put forward more requirements for data governance. The unified metadata management platform Gravitino (planned to be donated to Apache incubator) can help enterprises clearly control their Data + AI assets, achieve multi-cloud and multi-engine support, unified management of data permissions, sensitive data identification, desensitization rule setting, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Everywhere: Open Source&#43;Wasm in Democratizing LLM Access</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/ai-1001.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/ai-1001.html</guid>
      <description>This talk focuses on democratizing AI, with open source Large Language Models (LLMs) and WebAssembly (Wasm), making AI accessible and efficient.
Inference is estimated to consume over 90% of computing resources for AI workloads. Wasm does not only reduce AI inference cost, but also boosts deployment and accessibility of Large Language Models (LLMs), enabling writing LLM apps on your PC and run everywhere – from the edge to cloud, high-end servers to low-power IoT devices, across CPUs and GPUs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Amoro (Incubating)：Explore community operations from zero</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/incubator-1061.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/incubator-1061.html</guid>
      <description>In March 2024, the Amoro project was successfully voted into the Apache Software Foundation Incubator. Amoro is a lakehouse management system built on a variety of open source data lake tables. This sharing will focus on The main line of Amoro&amp;rsquo;s development history and current situation, focusing on how Amoro implements the open source concept and The Apache Way, exploring how to operate the community with current AI tools, and some opportunities and challenges in the incubation process of the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache IoTDB : A distributed time series database with scalable partitioning and consensus algorithm</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/iot-1067.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/iot-1067.html</guid>
      <description>Apache IoTDB (Database for Internet of Things) is a high performance IoT-native distributed time series database system. In this session, we first give a brief introduction of IoTDB. Then, we discuss its scalable partitioning algorithm and its innovative load balancing. Following that, we present a unified framework for consensus algorithms that support various consensus algorithms, including a strong consistency consensus algorithm (Raft) implemented by Apache Ratis (a high performance Raft library) and a weak consistency consensus algorithm based on asynchronous replication ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Pulsar deployment practice in the cross-Kubernetes cluster scenario</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1007.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/cloudnative-1007.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Pulsar clusters are usually formed by Apache Pulsar, Apache ZooKeeper, Apache BookKeepr, etc., where Apache ZooKeeper, Apache BookKeeper are usually served as a StatefulSet in Kubernetes. In the case of cross-Kubernetes cluster deployments, these components often face issues such as how to maintain a uniform sequential index across multiple clusters, and how to maintain a minimum number of available cluster replicas. This topic explores how the Apache Pulsar can be deployed in the cross-Kubernetes cluster scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Tomcat Performance with Virtual Threads</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/webserver-1133.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/webserver-1133.html</guid>
      <description>In this session, I will share how tomcat cooperates with virtual thread to improve application performance and some considerations, such as limitations of virtual threads.
Speakers: Han Li: Apache Tomcat PMC member, Han Li is a Senior Engineer at Netease Youdao(NetEase Youdao Information Technology (Beijing) Co., Ltd.), He is a committer and PMC member of Apache Tomcat.x000D </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration and Practice of Big Data Scheduling with Apache Dolphinscheduler in Alibaba Cloud</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/dataops-1056.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/dataops-1056.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Dolphinscheduler is a distributed and easily scalable workflow scheduling platform that can help users achieve efficient and reliable workflow scheduling and management. Alibaba Cloud EMR Workflow is a cloud-native serverless big data developing and scheduling platform built on Apache Dolphinscheduler. This speech will share the exploration and practice of EMR Workflow based on Apache Dolphinscheduler from the perspectives of ease of use, scalability, and stability.
Speakers: Xin Cheng: SDE with Alibaba Cloud, Apache Dolphinscheduler Committer, Xin Cheng received the B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of the Apache Way: OpenRank Practice from Alibaba</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1020.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1020.html</guid>
      <description>In this session, I will give a comprehensive introduction about a research practice with Alibaba OSPO. We developed a contribution evaluation algorithm with develop social network called OpenRank and use the result to build a gamification mechanism to motivate collaborations among developers in Alibaba open source communities. The OpenRank algorithm is deeply inspired by the Apache Way, especially &amp;ldquo;community over code&amp;rdquo;.
And the research of the practice is also summarized as a research paper and has been accepted by the top academic conference - ICSE 2024.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Apache Celeborn and Apache Gluten for Cloud-Native Shuffle</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1109.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1109.html</guid>
      <description>The session explores the integration of Apache Celeborn (Incubating) and Apache Gluten(incubating), a new incubating Apache project for native SQL engine support, to enhance Apache Spark&amp;rsquo;s performance in big data computing environments. Gluten addresses CPU computation bottlenecks by utilizing native engines like Velox and ClickHouse and introduces a Columnar Shuffle mechanism. The integration of Celeborn, a Remote Shuffle Service, into Gluten enhances Spark&amp;rsquo;s performance, stability, and elasticity. Performance tests show improved results in different environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application and Practice of Apache Linkis in Longbridge Securities</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1108.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1108.html</guid>
      <description>In the financial sector today, big data has emerged as a critical driver for business innovation and competitiveness enhancement. Longbridge Securities, a renowned financial services enterprise, has been committed to leveraging advanced technologies to boost its data processing and analysis capabilities for better client service and operational optimization. Apache Linkis, as a software solution, has become a key partner for Longbridge Securities in the realm of big data due to its robust data processing capabilities, flexible resource scheduling mechanisms, and rigorous security management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale production practice of cloud-native message system Apache Pulsar on Tencent Cloud</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1087.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1087.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Pulsar is is an cloud-native, distributed messaging and streaming platform. Apache Pulsar adopts a storage and computing separation architecture.Support large clusters, multi-tenants, million-level topics, cross-regional data replication, persistent storage, tiered storage, high scalability and other enterprise-level and financial services. Apache Pulsar provides a unified consumption model that supports both message queue and streaming scenarios. It can not only provide enterprise-level read and write service quality and strong consistency guarantee for queue scenarios, but also provide high throughput and low latency for streaming scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ResilientDB, a High Throughput Yielding Permissioned Blockchain Fabric</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1050.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1050.html</guid>
      <description>ResilientDB is a distributed blockchain framework that is open-source, lightweight, modular, and highly performant.
ResilientDB is a High Throughput Yielding Permissioned Blockchain Fabric founded by ExpoLab at UC Davis in 2018. ResilientDB advocates a system-centric design by adopting a multi-threaded architecture that encompasses deep pipelines. Further, ResilientDB modulizes each component (network, consensus protocols, and applications) enabling each level of developers to focus on their majors.
Speakers: Junchao Chen: PhD student from UC Davis, author of ResilientDB, A former core engineer at WeChat, Tencent from 2011 to 2017, Responsible for the backend message systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bigtop and Bigtop-Manager with openEuler: New Era of Big Data Distribution</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datalake-1037.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datalake-1037.html</guid>
      <description>At present, there are no available free bigdata component management platforms for streamlined data management and analytics. This is because the Cloudera Data Platform (CDP) is no longer free.
With a growing interest in similar platforms, Apache Bigtop and its incubator project, Bigtop-Manager, step in as free open-source alternatives to CDP. These alternatives are designed to provide a simpler and quicker approach to data management and analytics.
Furthermore, openEuler has over 300 organization members and has seen significant enterprise deployments, especially in China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Soft Skills for a successful Open Source career</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1019.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1019.html</guid>
      <description>Open source isn&amp;rsquo;t just about code. This session discusses the critical role of soft skills in building a successful career within the open source community around Apache projects. Learn how to effectively communicate, collaborate, and navigate challenges to become a well-rounded and valuable open source contributor.
Attendees will learn:
-Crafting clear documentation, presentations, and code comments for seamless collaboration within projects. -Strategies for building trust, resolving conflict constructively, and working effectively within diverse teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we use Reclaimed Low-Cost Computing Resouces for Large-Scale Near-Line Model Inference</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1132.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1132.html</guid>
      <description>Due to the increasing value of GPU resources, we have restructured Xiaohongshu&amp;rsquo;s image search system to create a near-line/offline inference pipeline, ultimately developing a high-quality cost-saving and efficiency-improving solution that utilizes idle computing resources to handle billions of data-scale model inference tasks:
In the transient and easily evictable resource pool with tidal characteristics, we have set up a virtualized k8s cluster to enable the submission of Flink jobs. Collaborating with the business team, we simplified the complex inference pipeline of the image search system, which previously consisted of over 10 microservices, into a few PyFlink jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-Depth Implementation of Apache Kyuubi in Xiaomi&#39;s OLAP Systems</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1107.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1107.html</guid>
      <description>Unified SQL Gateway for Big Data Security, SQL Traffic Management, and Usability  Masking the differences in access methods of various underlying engines, a consistent SQL service entry point is provided to users. It is compatible with Hive JDBC and supports HTTP access, offering convenience for integration with BI tools and SQL IDEs such as Apache Superset, Cloudera Hue, DataGrip, DBeaver, PowerBI, and Tableau. At the lower layer, it interfaces with mainstream computing and analytical engines like Spark, Trino, JDBC (Mysql/Postgres/Impala/Doris), and Flink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice on improving Xiaomi RocketMQ service product</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1086.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1086.html</guid>
      <description>This sharing mainly introduces Xiaomi’s practice in improving the product strength of RocketMQ, mainly including the improvement of the stability of the RocketMQ service itself and the practice of improving the strength of surrounding products such as Flink RocketMQ, Schema, MQTT and other services.
Speakers: Kunming Han: Xiaomi, Software R&amp;amp;D Engineer, Mainly responsible for message queue related work in Xiaomi </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognize, Reconcile, Repeat: The Path to Uniform Replicas in Apache Ozone</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1049.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1049.html</guid>
      <description>Faults in distributed systems often are unbounded. Apache Ozone needs to be resistant to faults and preserve the durability and consistency of data in the face of these faults. Reconciliation is a new feature being developed that allows Ozone to recover from faults independent of how they occurred as well as the duration between faults. Reconciliation allows peers to identify, report, and resolve discrepancies of any type, and works across data durability models such as replication as well as erasure coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Detail About Dependent Task</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/dataops-1055.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/dataops-1055.html</guid>
      <description>Dependent Task is an advanced feature in Apache DolphinScheduler, which provides users with amazing flexibility in managing complicated Cross-DAG dependencies. However, due to its complexity and evolutions across different release versions, sometimes users are confused with its behavior. This presentation will walk you through what dependent task is, how it works and every detail about it!
Speakers: Chufeng Gao: SDE@Alibaba Cloud, PMC Member@Apache DolphinScheduler, Chufeng Gao is a software engineer at EMR Serverless Spark team of Alibaba Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Code to Community: A Developer&#39;s Journey at StreamPark</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1018.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1018.html</guid>
      <description>Join my talk to explore the comprehensive experience of a developer in the Apache StreamPark project. From initial coding attempts to deep community engagement, I will share the technical challenges faced, solutions implemented, and collaborations with other developers throughout this journey. This presentation is not only an analysis of StreamPark&amp;rsquo;s functionalities but also an exploration of personal growth and the power of community. Hear me narrate how I found my place in this open-source project, witnessed the integration of technology and human insight through practical examples, and embraced the opportunities found amidst challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights and Design Analysis of the Apache Paimon Data Lake Architecture</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datalake-1036.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datalake-1036.html</guid>
      <description>In this presentation, I will delve into the core implementation details of the Apache Paimon Data Lake project.
1.I will introduce the logic behind CDC Ingestion, a crucial data synchronization mechanism that allows for the real-time capture and integration of data changes. This ensures that the information within the data lake is always up-to-date. 2.I will discuss in detail the read and write processes of Paimon tables, along with the design philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Tiered Storage Practice and Optimization in Huawei Cloud</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1085.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1085.html</guid>
      <description>This session will analyze the pain points of native Kafka in actual production, explain the Kafka tiered storage architecture and principles, and provide a detailed introduction to the practice and optimization of tiered storage in Huawei Cloud, and finally give a future outlook for Huawei Cloud Kafka.
Speakers: Lan Ding: nan, Huawei Cloud message engine R&amp;amp;D expert, Software engineer of Huawei Cloud Middleware Team, Apache RocketMQ Contributor, Apache Kafka Contributor, responsible for the development of Huawei Cloud Kafka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stability and Performance Optimization Practices of HBase at Xiaomi</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1048.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1048.html</guid>
      <description>Background This section will primarily introduce the current status and scale of HBase applications within Xiaomi, along with encountered challenges. Additionally, it will cover some internal optimization measures implemented and the benefits gained thereafter. Approaches and Practices 2.1 Stability Practices
 Hotspot Region Handling Business hotspot requests leading to queue congestion, impacting read/write operations of other regions; addressing this by isolating hotspot regions onto nodes with lower loads. TPS Load Balancing Existing balance solutions not effectively handling sudden spikes in request volume, resulting in uneven TPS loads; introducing TPS load balancing to mitigate these issues in line with Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s internal usage scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Practices of Apache Doris in Caitong Securities</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1106.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1106.html</guid>
      <description>Introduce the use cases of Apache Doris in Caitong Securities.
Speakers: Asher Wang: data architect, More than 15+ years expirences on data warehousing and bigdata. Now act as Bigdata Architect in Caitong Securities. Responsible for bigdata infrasturcture, data integration, data platform and etc. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xiaomi&#39;s Practice in Flink Stability Optimization and Business Efficiency Improvement with Paimon</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1131.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1131.html</guid>
      <description>This sharing mainly introduces some optimizations of Xiaomi in terms of stability and case sharing of Flink+Paimon in helping Xiaomi improve business production efficiency.
 Flink Stability Optimization 1.1Flink High Availability (HA) Capability Construction Fault tolerance is very important in production. This segment primarily discusses Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s efforts in establishing robust high-availability (HA) capabilities within its job processing architecture, specifically delving into mechanisms such as Checkpoint High Availability and MQ High Availability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BitSail: A Universal Data Integration Framework Built on Apache Ecosystem</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1130.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1130.html</guid>
      <description>In this presentation, we will explore the practical applications of BitSail within the Apache ecosystem, focusing on the design and implementation of a universal data integration framework powered by Apache Flink.
We will discuss the challenges and solutions involved in architecting a scalable and efficient framework that facilitates seamless data integration.
Additionally, the session will cover how BitSail connects with various Apache open-source data sources, enhancing connectivity and data flow between diverse systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File Runtime Statistics for Spark Optimization</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1105.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1105.html</guid>
      <description>In this demonstration, we will explore the application of statistics based on parquet files in the SparkSQL optimizer, focusing on the implementation of cost-based optimizations using these statistics.
We will discuss the challenges in the Query optimization and how to collect statistics in a low cost way.
In addition, we will share some cost-based optimization rules, including exchange elimination, bloom filter pushdown, parallelism estimation, etc., and show how to use statistical information to avoid Bad cases in these optimization rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practices of Kafka Cloud-Native Architecture at XiaoHongShu Company</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1047.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1047.html</guid>
      <description>In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll introduce the practices of Kafka Cloud-Native Architecture in our company, including the tiered storage base on ObjectStore, the k8s-based deployment architecture and the auto-balance/auto-scale mode based on these architectures.
Speakers: Yihao Zhang: 小红书大数据存储架构专家, Head of the Big Data Storage Team at Xiaohongshu. Currently responsible for the construction of Xiaohongshu&amp;rsquo;s data streaming engine, such as Apache Kafka, and the distributed file acceleration system, among other areas. Zhangheng Huang: 小红书消息引擎研发专家, Committer of Apache/RocketMQ and SOFASTACK/SOFAJRaft_x000D_ Currently focusing on the exploration and practice of cloud-native messaging system </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Batch Message in Apache RocketMQ</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1084.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1084.html</guid>
      <description>From the model design of RocketMQ to its internal mechanics, this topic comprehensively analyzes the iterative evolution of the batch message features in RocketMQ. Through continuous and relentless iteration, the AutoBatch feature is implemented, enhancing usability while achieving performance that reaches advanced industry levels, thus meeting various business needs. This subject not only shares the principles of RocketMQ and the evolution of batch processing, but also includes performance optimization related to batch message, which I believe will provide some different perspectives for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Practice of Data&amp;AI Integration of Lake and Warehouse in Xiaomi</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datalake-1035.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datalake-1035.html</guid>
      <description>This sharing mainly introduces Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s practice of data lake in Data and AI scenarios. In BI scenarios, we will introduce the business practices and intelligent optimization strategies of using Apache Iceberg. In AI scenarios, we will introduce the management for unstructured data. In addition, we will introduce our solutions for metadata unification using Gravitino in Data and AI scenarios.
 Optimization and Practice of Apache Iceberg in Xiaomi   The practice of Apache Iceberg  Apache Iceberg manages tens of thousands of tables and nearly 50 PB of data within Xiaomi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unicom Digital Technology&#39;s integrated data asset platform, built on Apache DolphinScheduler</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/dataops-1054.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/dataops-1054.html</guid>
      <description>Based on Apache dolphinscheduler, the entire data processing link is connected in series, from data collection to full-process operation management of data application. Match the code data research and development platform to transform data exploration and data research and development into low-cost and high-efficiency directions. Intelligent practical solutions for standards, BI, and data development  Speakers: Liu Wu: Senior big data development engineer, I has many years of experience in system management and platform development related to big data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What can I do to become an Apache Committer?</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1017.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1017.html</guid>
      <description>Why contribute to open source? My perspective on open source is that it is truly remarkable to browse the homepages and project lists of major companies and foundations on GitHub. It&amp;rsquo;s inspiring to see how they selflessly share their labor and contribute their achievements to the entire human society, fostering industry and social development.
Why become an Apache Committer? Becoming an Apache Committer offers numerous benefits, including personal professional growth, networking with talented peers, endorsement of individual capabilities through Apache email and a Committer certificate, enhanced competitiveness in the job market, active and extensive involvement in project development, improved professional image in the industry, free use of JetBrains tools, industry recognition acknowledged both domestically and internationally without any geographical boundaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application and Challenges of Apache ECharts in the Intelligent Operations Industry</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1104.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1104.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction to the Operations Industry
 Industry Overview  A brief description of the operations industry.   Industry Characteristics  Specific traits of the industry.   IT Assets, Log Scenarios, Alert Scenarios, ITIL  Comprehensive discussion of IT assets, log scenarios, alert mechanisms, and the use of ITIL.   Large Amount of Data  The industry generates a massive amount of data, necessitating strong visualization requirements, leading to deep integration with ECharts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Apache RocketMQ Storage</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1083.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1083.html</guid>
      <description>Messaging systems have evolved alongside the concepts of cloud native and microservices, witnessing the vitality of highly dynamic and asynchronous systems such as serverless and event-driven architectures. Consequently, the architecture and models of message queues themselves have undergone significant changes. This talk presents how a data-intensive application introduces new solutions to support massive queues during its modernization journey. It will cover tiered storage capabilities and new index designs, granular traffic control for warm and hot data, as well as experiments with cloud-native storage and integrated hardware-software technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobilize Your Community Army: A Commercial OpenSource&#39;s Perspective</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1016.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1016.html</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s developer relations are inevitably tied to open-source software and its communities. Understanding different open source communities by category and formulating open source strategies within the corporate strategy framework to form good interactions with open source developers and jointly create value has become a topic that developer relations workers must understand and master.
This speech first classifies open source communities from multiple dimensions to clarify the characteristics and modes of getting along with different communities; then discusses how commercial open source should adapt to different corporate strategies and open source community categories; finally, it gives an example of the relationship between open source developers The entry point of work includes how to establish corresponding portraits and segmentations, and how to carry out specific job based on content and coordination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Lakehouse with Confidence: Best Practices for Implementation with Apache Iceberg</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datalake-1034.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datalake-1034.html</guid>
      <description>The convergence of data lakes and data warehouses into a unified architecture, known as the Lakehouse paradigm, has gained significant traction in the data engineering community. Apache Iceberg has emerged as a cornerstone technology for implementing Lakehouse architectures, providing robust features for managing large-scale, transactional data lakes efficiently. In this session, we will explore best practices for implementing a Lakehouse architecture using Apache Iceberg. Through real-world examples and practical insights, attendees will learn how to design, deploy, and optimize a Lakehouse solution that leverages the strengths of Iceberg for data management, reliability, and performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice and application of Apache Flink CDC in Huolala</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1129.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1129.html</guid>
      <description>Lalamove &amp;amp; Huolala is an on-demand delivery platform born with a mission to empower communities by making delivery fast, simple and affordable.
Practice on the community&amp;rsquo;s latest Apache Flink CDC 3.0 and use it in production. Now running 100+ tasks, we share the challenges and problems encountered in our production practice and give back to the community
Speakers: Zheng Yu Chen: Apache Amoro PPMC , HuoLaLa Senior Big Data Dev, Chen Zheng Yu (ConradJam), Apache Flink Chinese community volunteer, has been engaged in data development in the game industry for a long time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice On Full-link Data Monitoring in Xiaomi Data Integration</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/dataops-1053.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/dataops-1053.html</guid>
      <description>This speech introduces Xiaomi’s construction of a visual full-link data monitoring system in data integration practice.
The focus of this sharing is on the implementation of data integration full-link data monitoring technology in Xiaomi. Starting from the data integration link system, in view of the reliability challenges encountered in data integration practice, from the perspective of the visual full-link data monitoring construction plan Share and explain aspects such as proposal and implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Production Practices of Apache Celeborn on Bilibili</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1046.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1046.html</guid>
      <description> Introduce the latest features of Apache Celeborn Introduce the best practices of Apache Celeborn on Bilibili Provide a brief overview of Apache Celeborn&amp;rsquo;s execution on Bilibili Outline the future practical plans for Apache Celeborn  Speakers: Nicholas Jiang:Bilibili,Senior Development Engineer, Apache Celeborn/Kyuubi/RocketMQ Committer, Apache Paimon PPMC </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache SeaTunnel realizes the efficient data synchronization of batch and stream integration based o</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/dataops-1052.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/dataops-1052.html</guid>
      <description>How does Apache SeaTunnel structure on Flink to construct an efficient data integration tool
Speakers: Chao Tian: Apache SeaTunnel PMC Member, Open source enthusiasts, who have contributed to some data integration projects such as DataX, Flink CDC, Debezium, Chunjun, etc., is an Apache SeaTunnel PMC Member. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache StreamPark High Scalability Practice</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1128.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1128.html</guid>
      <description>Introduce Apache StreamPark&amp;rsquo;s plugin-based extension capabilities and engineering solutions, demonstrate how plugin development can adapt to various business scenarios, and demonstrate integrated solutions with Flink CDC and Paimon.
Speakers: Xinyu Dai: Apache StreamPark community, Bigdata software engineer, Apache StreamPark/Paimon Contributor </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitino Iceberg REST catalog service, why and beyond</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datalake-1033.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datalake-1033.html</guid>
      <description>this session will introduce why the Iceberg community introduce Iceberg REST catalog and the latest progress about REST catalog. Why Gravitino integrate the Iceberg REST catalog service , the future of it.
Speakers: Xiaojing Fang: datastrato, software engineer, ten years of experience in the big data area, formally working in Alibaba, Tencent, and Kwaishoud about distributed computation and scheduling systems. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Serverless Architecture In Tencent Cloud</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1082.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1082.html</guid>
      <description>Kafka is widely used in Tencent Cloud. Because of Kafka architecture issues, there is a lot of operational pressure. In order to ensure stability and cost in advance, a set of Kafka serverless architecture is gradually explored. This sharing will introduce the evolution process and experience of Tencent Cloud Kafka serverless architecture.
Speakers: Shilin Lu: 腾讯云计算（北京）有限责任公司，北京市海淀区马连洼街道腾讯总部大楼，腾讯云专家工程师, I graduated from Tianjin University majoring in software engineering. At present, I am responsible for the development and optimization of Kafka kernel in Tencent Cloud, and have 7 years of experience in the development and operation and maintenance of message middleware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Story of Launching an Open Source Project from Scratch</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1015.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1015.html</guid>
      <description>The popularity of open source has been on the rise in recent years. Many companies are actively participating in upstream open source projects and making contributions. They are also taking the initiative to open source their mature solutions.
However, launching an open source project from scratch can be challenging for most small and medium teams. In the past year, I had the opportunity to do this work in one startup, including project initiation, decision-making, planning, building, organizing, and final public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization for Reducing Compute Cost of SparkSQL in ByteDance</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1000.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1000.html</guid>
      <description>ByteDance employs SparkSQL as one of the primary tools for ETL. Through analysis of online tasks, it was discovered that three major factors contribute to the degradation of Spark job performance: shuffling large volumes of data, scanning numerous small files, and inefficient speculative execution. Shuffling large volumes of data may lead to issues such as network congestion, IO bottlenecks, and affecting the stability of the Shuffle Service. Reading numerous small files increases data transmission overhead and memory usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Apache HoraeDB for High-Cardinality Metrics at AntGroup</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1103.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1103.html</guid>
      <description>High cardinality is a significant challenge for time series databases (TSDBs). This can occur when the metric is tracking a large number of entities, or when the metric itself has a high number of possible values. Traditional time-series databases are often not optimized to handle large numbers of unique value combinations, leading to performance degradation and inefficiencies when dealing with high-cardinality metrics. This topic will explore how Apache HoraeDB tackles this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancements and Enhancements in Apache DolphinScheduler with Kubernetes</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/dataops-1051.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/dataops-1051.html</guid>
      <description>Cisco Webex improves and enhances with Apache DolphinScheduler and Kubernetes
Speakers: Qingwang Li: Cisco Webex, Software Engineer, Cisco Webex, Software Engineer, Apache DolphinScheduler Committer </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Doris Separation of Storage and Compute</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1102.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1102.html</guid>
      <description>Shares the architecture, detailed design, and use cases of Apache Doris Separation of Storage and Compute
Speakers: Gavin Chou: Senior R&amp;amp;D Engineer at SelectDB, I worked on distributed/cloud storage systems, I&amp;rsquo;m currently learning and working on OLAP databases at SelectDB. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application practice of China Unicom’s streaming lakehouse based on Apache Paimon</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datalake-1032.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datalake-1032.html</guid>
      <description>This topic plans to introduce China Unicom’s practical experience in building a streaming data warehouse based on Apache Paimon, which mainly includes two core business projects of China Unicom: real-time user tags and natural persons. It will cover business background, streaming-batch integrated data warehouse architecture, problems encountered in practice and corresponding solutions, the benefits achieved by using Apache Paimon to solve the problems, and future plans will be introduced.
Speakers: Yunpeng Wang: Apache Paimon Contributor; currently a big data technology expert in the Data Intelligence Division of China Unicom Digital Technology Co.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-AZ evolution of RocketMQ based on kosmos in ChinaMobile Cloud</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1081.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1081.html</guid>
      <description>This talk will introduce the evolution of RocketMQ in the cross-az aspects of China Mobile Cloud, and discuss the best practices of multi-cluster architecture in cross availability zone disaster recovery scenarios. Then discuss the evolution, benefits, and challenges of Kubernetes multi-cluster architecture. We will share the evolution process of ecloud (chinamobile cloud) multi-cluster architecture from KubeFed to Karmada to Kosmos, and summarize the experiences and lessons learned along the way. In this talk,listeners will gain a comprehensive understanding of Kubernetes multi-cluster architecture and learn how to leverage it to optimize cloud-native applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration and Practice of Flink SQL Performance Optimization at ByteDance.</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1127.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1127.html</guid>
      <description>With the internal demand for streaming tasks at Bytedance escalating on a daily basis, the large-scale implementation of Flink SQL has become increasingly prevalent across multiple departments. Flink SQL, being a cost-effective entry-point, has seen the scale of streaming SQL tasks elevate to over 30K, while task resource utilization has reached several million cores. Amidst the corporate emphasis on cost reduction and efficiency augmentation, we have undertaken a multitude of performance enhancements in the areas of Query Optimization and Query Execution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating the Apache Cassandra Java Driver with OpenTelemetry for End-to-End Tracing</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1045.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1045.html</guid>
      <description>In today’s distributed system architectures, including Apache Cassandra distributed database, troubleshooting is a major challenge. Despite many observability frameworks, compatibility and configuration issues persist. OpenTelemetry has changed the game by standardizing observability data collection. This talk will demonstrate integrating the Apache Cassandra Java Driver with OpenTelemetry for end-to-end tracing, showing how to collect and visualize tracing events for analysis. This significantly speeds up diagnosing issues and resolving performance bottlenecks. We&amp;rsquo;ll also share real-world examples to highlight the importance of end-to-end tracing in enhancing system robustness and observability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One more thing about ASF and its projects from China</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/community-1014.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/community-1014.html</guid>
      <description>The open-source movement in China has been thriving for over a decade, making it the second-largest country in the world regarding the number of open-source developers and contributors after the United States. &amp;ldquo;The 2023 China Open Source Report&amp;rdquo; sheds light on China&amp;rsquo;s open-source development from various perspectives, including developers, technologies, projects, communities, enterprises, education, foundations, open-source commercialization, and domestic and international open-source chronicles. This sharing will focus more on ASF and its projects, especially those from China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impala 4.4: A More Intelligent Query Engine</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1101.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1101.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Impala is a native query engine implemented in MPP architecture for open data and table formats. In this session, we will share the updates in the Impala community during the past year, including the core features of the upcoming 4.4 release, e.g. Workload Aware Auto-Scaling, Calcite integration, JDBC Federation, Codegen caching, Intermediate Results Caching, Query History Table, etc.
Speakers: Quanlong Huang: Cloudera, Senior Staff Engineer, Quanlong Huang is a software engineer at Cloudera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless architecture upgrade based on Apache Kafka</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1080.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1080.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Kafka Community Edition is an excellent distributed event streaming platform, but due to its integrated design of computing and storage, its elasticity is poor and the cost of operating large-scale clusters is high. Alibaba Cloud Kafka has been fully upgraded based on the open-source Kafka, combining cloud-native infrastructure such as elastic computing, high-performance distributed file storage, and container services to achieve the cloud-nativeization of Kafka. It has low latency, high throughput, extreme elasticity, and easier operation and maintenance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Iceberg Table Lifecycle Management: A Comprehensive Approach</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1044.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1044.html</guid>
      <description>Iceberg tables have emerged as a powerful solution for managing large-scale data lakes, offering features like ACID compliant transactions, efficient data organization, and schema evolution. However, as data lakes grow in complexity, so do the challenges in managing the lifecycle of Iceberg tables effectively. This session will delve into strategies for simplifying the management of Iceberg tables throughout their lifecycle. We will explore techniques for optimizing table creation, time travel, compaction, schema evolution, data retention, and archival processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standardized Monolithic/Microservice Traffic Management - Koal Safety Tech Co.&#39;s Higress Practice</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/api-1094.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/api-1094.html</guid>
      <description>Koal Safety Technology Co. using Higress as the API Gateway, and adopting the latest K8s Gateway API standard to replace Nginx. It has achieved a unified and standardized entry traffic management mechanism for monolithic/microservices.
Speakers: Tianyi Zhang: Alibaba Cloud, API Gateway, Proficient Engineer, Alibaba Cloud API Gateway Engineer, Maintainer of Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s open-source gateway Higress. ZhengHao Zhang: Koal Software Co., envoy gateway, Senior Software Engineer, envoy云原生网关负责人，alibaba higress 开源项目贡献者，前戴尔科技以及中国电科第50研究所软件工程师，有丰富的nginx&amp;amp;envoy实战经验，拥抱开源，对开源技术以及云原生技术有着浓厚的兴趣。 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The best pratice of integration technology driven by event  in cloud</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/others-1117.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/others-1117.html</guid>
      <description>In the past decade, there has been a significant shift in user demands for modern applications. Users expect applications to handle and respond to their needs in real-time, and to be consistently available. Additionally, applications face unprecedented volumes of data being transmitted from client to server, including real-time data, cloud computing events, messages from distributed business systems, and massive data from big data sources. Users also expect new applications to be rapidly developed and deployed with features and updates, incorporating agile methodologies and DevOps practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache EventMesh事件网格助力构建事件平台</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1079.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1079.html</guid>
      <description>介绍ApacheEventMesh 在吉利汽车的一些典型的使用场景，如何构建事件平台并在生产环境中的落地实践。
Speakers: Fazhan Qiao: 吉利汽车集团，IT基础设施架构师, 就职于吉利汽车集团，负责IT基础设施系统集成及治理。构建API网关、消息集成、事件集成、数据集成、IOT集成等产品能力。使用 Apache Eventmesh 产品并参与社区建设。 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Real-Time Data Integration with Flink CDC</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1126.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1126.html</guid>
      <description>In an age where data velocity and volume escalate rapidly, Apache Flink combined with Change Data Capture (CDC) technology presents a transformative solution for real-time data integration. This talk will dive into the architecture and implementation of Flink CDC, highlighting how this combination facilitates real-time data synchronization, analytics, and decision-making across various industries.
Speakers: Qingsheng Ren: Apache Flink Committer and PMC Member, Qingsheng Ren is Apache Flink committer and PMC member.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Elasticsearch to Apache Doris: Real-time Analysis and Unified Log Retrieval, Practice of Financ</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1100.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1100.html</guid>
      <description>From Elasticsearch to Apache Doris: Real-time Analysis and Unified Log Retrieval, Practice of Financial Security Data Architecture Upgrade for ChinaTelecom Bestpay
Speakers: Jianqun liu: China Telecom Bestpay Co.,Ltd. Technical Director , ChinaTelecom Senior Security Specialist ，10+ years of R&amp;amp;D and architecture experience </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Performance IoT Data Replication Over Raft</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1043.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1043.html</guid>
      <description>Firstly, this session will introduce Apache IoTDB, IoT native distributed database and its high-availability design considerations. Then the session talks about the rationale behind choosing the Raft consensus algorithm and Apache Ratis library. After that, the session will give an overview of how Apache IoTDB uses Apache Ratis, its considerations and improvements. Finally, the session will talk about IoT-specific optimizations on Raft, namely, Non-Blocking Raft and community&amp;rsquo;s plans on implementing ande deploying NB-Raft on IoTDB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play with WASM</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/others-1116.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/others-1116.html</guid>
      <description>What wonderful reactions do Apache projects produce when combined with WASM ? Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about ShenYu, dubbo, and pulsar.
Speakers: ZiCheng Zhang: ShenYu, Hello everyone, my name is ZiCheng Zhang. I&amp;rsquo;m a Java developer and rust fan, who graduated from Jiangxi Normal University. In February 2021, I collaborated with @hengyunabc to create vmtool in arthas. In April 2022, I became the ShenYu committer and created MemorySafeLinkedBlockingQueue. One month later, I joined the ShenYu PMC team and started to build an stackfull coroutine crate named open-coroutine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice of building a lakehouse based on Hudi at Kuaishou Inc</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datalake-1031.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datalake-1031.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Hudi reimagines slow old-school batch data processing with powerful new incremental processing framework for low latency minute-level analytics. In this sharing, we will first introduce the headache of the traditional data warehouse. Then we describe how to solve those problems based on HUDI. Finally, we give a few user cases atKuaishou to introduce the benefits after using HUDI to replace their old-school pipelines.
Speakers: Zhang Jing: Kuaishou Inc, Technical expert, Zhangjing, Software Engineer at Kuaishou Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seata Architecture Evolution: Best Practices for Client and Server Deployment Forms</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/api-1093.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/api-1093.html</guid>
      <description>This content will introduce the network communication architecture of the Seata client, and how to perfectly combine it with the server in different store modes and register types, so that both the client and the server can achieve an ideal high-availability form, and in the future deployment form What changes are likely to occur? How will future architecture evolution make Seata more mature and the ecological architecture more closed-loop, save users&#39; operation and maintenance deployment costs, lower the threshold for entry-level learning, be close to users&#39; traditional usage habits, and be as mature as other top-level middleware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better evaluation for Text2SQL by using Apache Calcite</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1099.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1099.html</guid>
      <description>English: LLM is increasingly being applied in work and life. Using dialogue to generate SQL with LLM will help improve the efficiency of data analysis. No matter what LLM is used to generate SQL, there are always some problems with evaluating the generated SQL:
 How to achieve equivalence judgment for different SQL dialects? How to achieve equivalence judgment for functions with the same semantics but different names? How to achieve equivalence judgment for SQL with different intermediate logic and the same final result?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an inclusive Open Source Ecosystem</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/others-1115.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/others-1115.html</guid>
      <description>The Apache Software Foundation (ASF) thrives on innovation fueled by diverse perspectives. This session discusses the strategies for building a more inclusive and welcoming environment for everyone, regardless of background, experience level, or technical expertise.
Attendees will gain knowledge on:
 We&amp;rsquo;ll explore unconscious bias and its potential impact on inclusivity within the open source community. Discover strategies for promoting diversity in project teams and fostering a culture of respect for different approaches and skillsets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HStream: Modern Streaming Data Platform Compatible with Kafka Protocol</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1125.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1125.html</guid>
      <description>HStream is a modern distributed streaming data platform compatible with the Kafka protocol. It is open-sourced at https://github.com/hstreamdb/hstream. With its cloud-native architectural design and storage engine optimized for large-scale streaming data, HStream successfully eliminates many of Apache Kafka&amp;rsquo;s pain points, allowing users to efficiently complete one-stop ingestion, storage, processing, and distribution of all real-time messages, events, and other data streams on a single platform.
In this session, we will introduce the technical evolution of streaming data platform, HStream&amp;rsquo;s technical architecture and streaming storage engine design, including how HStream solves Kafka&amp;rsquo;s pain points in fast elastic scaling, replica migration, load skewing, high data reliability, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices Architecture in Golang</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/api-1092.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/api-1092.html</guid>
      <description>Microservices Architecture in Golang
Speakers: Yuanxiao Zhao: AlibabaCloud, Microservices R&amp;amp;D Engineer </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Row-level modifications at petabyte-scale via Impala on Iceberg</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1042.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1042.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Impala is a distributed, massively parallel query engine for big data. Initially, it focused on fast query execution on top of large datasets that were ingested via long-running batch jobs. The table schema and the ingested data typically remained unchanged, and row-level modifications were impractical. Today&amp;rsquo;s expectations for modern data warehouse engines have risen significantly, users now want to have RDBMS-like capabilities in their data warehouses, e.g.: schema and partition evolution, time-travel, and the focus of this talk: row-level modification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Practice of KafkaConnect in Middleware Disaster Recovery</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1078.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1078.html</guid>
      <description>Kafka and RocketMQ are popular high-performance message middleware to ensure their high availability. This speech mainly introduces how to use KafkaConnect for message middleware, cross data center, cross cluster migration, and disaster recovery.
Speakers: Haijun Wang: Huawei Cloud, Message,Disaster recovery, Software engineer of Huawei Cloud Middleware Team </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application and exploration of Apache Doris in PSBC</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1098.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1098.html</guid>
      <description>Summarizing the application status and future application plan of Apache Doris in PSBC, and reflects the technical empowerment and business efficiency improvement brought by Apache Doris to the financial system.
Speakers: Cun Liu: PSBC, Data Engineer, Liu Cun, working in the Software Research and Development Center of PSBC, mainly responsible for data analysis, data mining and data maintenance. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing integration in easist &amp; cheapist way</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/others-1114.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/others-1114.html</guid>
      <description>Camel 4.X is a very new release. There are many new features being introduced for this integration project version. I will introduce the new features in Camel4.5, including Camel-K on cloud, JBang, Apache Camel Karavan 4.4.0 low code one-stop shop for simplified and accelerated integration development with Apache Camel, the supported platform includes quarkus and springboot. I will show you how fast and easy to meet the integration requirement in cloud natvie way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration and practice of distributed middleware benchmark mechanism represented by Dubbo</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/api-1091.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/api-1091.html</guid>
      <description>Compared with single frameworks, the construction of distributed middleware usually encounters more problems. For example, test automation, multi-process orchestration and scheduling, performance bottleneck analysis methods, etc. This article will take Dubbo as an example to explore a one-stop benchmark construction solution for distributed middleware.
Speakers: Xiaobin Wang: Development Engineer at Zhengcai Cloud Company, Apache Dubbo Committer </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impala discovers Iceberg Metadata Tables</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datalake-1030.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datalake-1030.html</guid>
      <description>Storing extensive metadata is one of the key features of the Apache Iceberg table format, helping query engines plan and execute queries efficiently. As Iceberg provides an API to query this metadata, it can be presented in query engines as a set of virtual tables, which can be queried with SQL, including filtering, aggregation and joins with other metadata or even regular tables. This feature provides an invaluable table maintenance tool for database administrators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixing Stream and Batch Processing in Apache Flink</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1124.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1124.html</guid>
      <description>For a long time, stream processing and batch processing have been the two distinct modes of large-scale data processing. With the development of unified stream and batch processing, Apache Flink now allows both to be managed within a single engine. This blurs the distinction between stream and batch processing, giving rise to a new unified data processing mode, known as mixed mode. In this mixed mode, users are not burdened with the need to pre-determine the execution mode for their Flink jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RocketMQ ACL 2.0：消息系统企业级安全体系的进化之路</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1077.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1077.html</guid>
      <description>RocketMQ, as a widely used distributed messaging middleware, relies on its ACL (Access Control List) mechanism to ensure system security. With the advancement of technology and the expansion of business scale, the original ACL 1.0 faces several security challenges, such as the misuse of IP whitelists, lack of fine-grained control, and access control between components. To address these issues, RocketMQ has introduced ACL 2.0, which incorporates mechanisms such as the separation of user authentication and permission verification, balancing security and performance, multiple matching modes for authorized resources, and flexible and extensible plugin architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts and Practices on Storage and Computing Separation Architecture at Xiaomi</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1041.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1041.html</guid>
      <description>In order to achieve ultimate cost-effectiveness, Xiaomi has carried out multi-stage exploration and technical practice in the domain of big data storage and computing architecture.
In terms of storage, we have built HDFS Tiering capabilities of object-based storage, and also implemented the storage of Apache Iceberg on the cloud; In the realm of computing, we have leveraged Yarn federation to achieve hybrid cloud scheduling, enabling us to expand our resources to include ARM-based machines and Spot instances, among other heterogeneous resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Kylin: 5.0 New Features Introduction</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1097.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1097.html</guid>
      <description>Kylin 5.0 GA version will be released in July 2024. This sharing session will introduce a series of heavyweight new features of Kylin 5.0, such as Calcite component upgrades, storage engine upgrades, intelligent modeling capabilities, metadata refactoring, integration of internal table functions with Native Engine, etc.
Speakers: Lu Cao: Kyligence, R&amp;amp;D Senior Manager, Lu is a Sr. R&amp;amp;D Manager at Kyligence and a committer of Apache Carbondata. He currently works on leading the Forward-looking R&amp;amp;D of OLAP team and focus on building next-gen OLAP analysis platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache StreamPark - A framework that make stream processing easier</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1123.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1123.html</guid>
      <description>Introduce why Apache StreamPark(Incubating) makes stream processing easier, what core problems it solves, how to use it, community development, and future plans.
Speakers: Huajie Wang: Apache StreamPark PPMC member, Founder of Apache StreamPark, PPMC member </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Apache Cassandra with EloqKV</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1040.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1040.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Cassandra is an exceptionally scalable, distributed NoSQL database engineered to manage vast quantities of data across numerous commodity servers, ensuring high availability without a single point of failure. In this session, we introduce a new project, EloqKV, which is built upon the robust foundation of Apache Cassandra. EloqKV enhances its capabilities by providing sub-millisecond read/write performance and full transaction support, functioning effectively as a consistent cache layer for Cassandra. Users can access the Data Substrate using the familiar Redis API, enjoying the speed of an in-memory database while leveraging Cassandra&amp;rsquo;s capacity to store large datasets comprehensively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiently managing and optimizing Apache Iceberg with Apache Amoro</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datalake-1029.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datalake-1029.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Iceberg as an open data lake table format, providing a highly open and efficient unified storage solution. In production, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to manage and optimize its files and metadata to achieve better performance and reduced overhead. Amoro, as a data lake management system, can compact Iceberg&amp;rsquo;s small files and delete files in real-time, enhance actual query performance. Additionally, it assists Iceberg in automatically performing maintenance processes such as expiring snapshots, cleaning orphaned data, and removing expired data, significantly reducing manual maintenance efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does Apache Dubbo switch between monolith and microservices</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/api-1090.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/api-1090.html</guid>
      <description>In recent years, the comparison between monolithic architecture and microservice architecture has once again appeared in everyone&amp;rsquo;s field of vision and has been widely discussed. There have even been cases of migration back to monolithic architecture from microservice architecture. So, is monolithic architecture superior, or is microservice architecture superior? There are no silver bullets in the software world, and the right choice is what suits you. Apache Dubbo has many excellent features and capabilities in the domain of microservice architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Multi-cluster Architecture over Kubernetes in ChinaMobile cloud</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1076.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1076.html</guid>
      <description>In this talk we will share the experience of multi-cluster kafka architecture over Kubernetes. We will introduce the best practices of manage CPU, memory, disk IO, network IO resource between each kafka clusters, the importent metrics of kafka clusters and pods, and the high-available architecture beetween multi Kubernetes clusters. In this talk, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to optimize your kafka deployment over Kubernetes.
Speakers: Jialing Wang: China Mobile, software engineer, Apache Kafka and Pulsar develop manager at China Mobile Cloud Center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of tools, techniques and tips - Scaling Ozone performance to max out CPU, Network and Disk</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/performance-1120.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/performance-1120.html</guid>
      <description>Over the past year, significant advancements have been made in enhancing the performance of Ozone, a distributed object store designed to scale on commodity hardware and capable of handling billions of files. These enhancements not only ensure that Ozone can saturate the network, provided the drives are sufficiently fast, but also improve the performance from a single-thread perspective during both read and write operations. This talk delves into the various tools and techniques employed to achieve these performance gains, highlighting key optimizations at the system level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMQP On RocketMQ Practice</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1075.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1075.html</guid>
      <description>The AMQP protocol is a standard application layer protocol in the field of message middleware. With its long history, active community, rich ecology, full coverage of multi-language SDK and other advantages, it has become one of the most widely used standard message protocols, even today, Kafka, RocketMQ, etc. Nowadays, distributed message queue products are popular, but they still occupy a place in the messaging field and are widely adopted by users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Gluten (Incubating): Boosting Apache Spark Performance with Native Engines</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1096.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1096.html</guid>
      <description>In early 2022, Intel and Kyligence unveiled Gluten, an open-source project succeeding the Gazelle project. Gazelle, an Apache Arrow-based native SQL engine by Intel, aimed to alleviate Spark SQL processing. Gluten supersedes Gazelle, amalgamating various native engines such as Velox and ClickHouse, providing performance enhancements for Apache Spark users. By connecting Spark with vectorized SQL engines, Gluten tackles performance hurdles and harnesses Advanced Vector Extensions (AVX) technology. The project offers components like the Gluten Plugin, Plan Conversion, Fallback Processing, Memory Management, Columnar Shuffle, Shim Layer, and Metrics, seamlessly integrating with Spark and native libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache HBase on Ozone</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1039.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1039.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Ozone is the next generation distributed storage system in the Hadoop ecosystem. It exposes both Hadoop Compatible File System API and S3 protocol compatible API. With the latest 1.4.0 version, Ozone has supported Apache Spark, YARN, Hive and Impala smoothly. Apache HBase, is a Bigtable-like data store, playing a very important role in the Hadoop ecosystem. In this session, I will share how the feature is designed, the challenges we have met, and the latest status of the development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Paimon: Unified Lake for Stream &amp; Batch &amp; OLAP</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datalake-1028.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datalake-1028.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Paimon is a lake format that enables building a Realtime Lakehouse Architecture with Flink and Spark for both streaming and batch operations. It entered the incubator last year and officially graduated as TLP this year. Growing from a Flink built-in storage to a universal storage format. This session introduces:
 Paimon starts with real-time updates to address the core issue of CDC data entering the lake. Paimon solves a large number of usability issues to build an offline data warehouse with Spark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic and Incremental Configuration Management for Flink Applications</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1122.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1122.html</guid>
      <description>In the rapidly evolving landscape of stream processing, Apache Flink has emerged as a powerful platform for developing robust, scalable, and real-time data processing applications. However, managing configurations for Flink applications in a dynamic environment poses significant challenges, including the need for flexibility, consistency, and the ability to adapt to changes without downtime. This technical session introduces a comprehensive approach adopted in eBay&amp;rsquo;s Notification Platform team to dynamic and incremental configuration management that simplifies the process of updating Flink application settings on-the-fly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring next stop of microservices, Koupleless modular development framework and serving system</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/api-1089.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/api-1089.html</guid>
      <description>The development of microservices has greatly solved the issue of organizational specialization. However, it has also introduced some challenges:
 Business developers need to be aware of complex infrastructure, leading to slow start-ups and low development efficiency. There is no standard for microservices decomposition. Insufficient decomposition may lead to collaboration blockers among team members, while over-decomposition may lead to resource usage and long-term maintenance cost issues. How to establish a rational standard for microservice decomposition to fundamentally avoid issues of under- or over-decomposition?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Apache Fury Serialization</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/performance-1119.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/performance-1119.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Fury is a blazingly fast multi-language serialization framework powered by JIT and zero-copy. The session will include four parts: ● Why we need a new serialization framework? ○ The lack of protobuf/flatbuffer/json ○ What is Fury ○ How fast is Fury compared to existing frameworks ○ The intuitive xlang programing model in Fury ● The serialization protocol in Fury ○ Introduction to fury xlang spec ○ How Fury support reference and polymorphism ○ How Fury support schema evolution ● Why Fury is so fast ○ How Runtime Codegen in java/python/nodejs speed serialization ○ Efficient codegen at compile time in C++/Rust ● The future of Fury</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Chapter: HugeGraph’s Self-controlled Storage, High-Performance Computing, and the Future of AI</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1038.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datastorage-1038.html</guid>
      <description>Main points:
 (Introduction) An overview diagram of the entire new version of GraphSystem (combining the latest various components/repositories). (Main) The first self-controlled storage distributed PD + Store version. (Based on Raft + RocksDB) (New Version) The Vermeer in-memory graph computing system + the new open-source version of Hubble. (New Repository/Exploration) New Graph AI repository/exploration content. (Conclusion) Future outlook and planning (LLM/GQL/Memory Management/RocksDB-Plus&amp;hellip;).  Speakers: Imba Jin: Apache HugeGraph PPMC member, HugeGraph PPMC member, currently responsible for the release management of the open source community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Queries on Apache Kyuubi with Apache Gluten and Velox Engine at NetEase</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/datalake-1027.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/datalake-1027.html</guid>
      <description>The session explores the collaborative use of Kyuubi, a pure SQL gateway, and Gluten, a vectorized execution engine, to enhance the performance of SQL queries. Kyuubi simplifies large-scale data manipulation for end-users through Thrift JDBC/ODBC interface or RESTful api, reducing barriers to lakehouse usage. Its multi-tenant architecture ensures resource isolation/sharing and data security on the server side. The session focuses on Netease&amp;rsquo;s implementation of Kyuubi with Gluten and Velox as the backend engine, aiming to address performance bottlenecks and sharing real-case results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Celeborn Community Evolution and Apache Flink Hybrid Shuffle Integration</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/streaming-1121.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/streaming-1121.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Celeborn, as an intermediate data service designed to boost performance, stability, and flexibility for Big Data compute engines, has made new progress in various areas including performance optimization, in-memory storage, security features, and improved stability. Concurrently, At Apache Community Over Code Asia 2023, Flink introduced a new hybrid shuffle architecture designed for dynamic adaptation between streaming and batch shuffle modes. The collaboration between Flink and Celeborn has further matured hybrid shuffle architecture and supports flexible switching between local and remote shuffles, allowing for simultaneously leveraging the benefits of both shuffle modes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Doris for efficient semi-structured data analysis</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/olap-1095.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/olap-1095.html</guid>
      <description>The characteristic and challenge of semi-structured data analysis. Traditional technology and new solutions from Apache Doris.
Speakers: Kang Xiao: SelectDB, VP, SelectDB, VP QianXin and 360, Director. Baidu, Senior Engineer </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Pulsar cluster scale control and stability practice</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/messaging-1074.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/messaging-1074.html</guid>
      <description>Whether it is service cloud nativeization or AI model training, the stability of the message queue as a basic component is increasingly important. The magnitude of upper-layer business is getting larger and larger, and the requirements for message queue performance and throughput are getting higher and higher. The continuous expansion of clusters will continue to expand the scale of the cluster. Large clusters are prone to problems such as hot spots and excessive explosion radius, which have always affected the stability of upper-layer services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Performance and Reliability of Dubbo in Cloud-Native Environments with HTTP/3</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/api-1088.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/api-1088.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Dubbo is a high-performance RPC framework dedicated to providing excellent service governance capabilities. With the introduction of HTTP/3, its features based on the QUIC protocol offer new possibilities for Dubbo microservices communication. HTTP/3, by reducing latency, increasing transmission speed, enhancing security, improving packet loss resistance, and supporting 0-RTT connections, provides significant performance and reliability improvements for Dubbo in cloud-native environments for microservices communication.
Speakers: Sean Yang: nan, Cloud Software Group(Citrix), Principal SW Engineer, 18 years of experience in Java architecture and development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s see how fast Impala runs on Iceberg</title>
      <link>/2024/sessions/performance-1118.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sessions/performance-1118.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Impala is a distributed massively parallel query engine designed for high-performance querying of large-scale data. There has been a long list of new features recently around supporting Apache Iceberg tables such as reading, writing, time traveling, and so on. However, in a big data environment it is also a must to be performant. Since Impala has been designed to be fast, it has its own way of reading Iceberg tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/2024/cfp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/cfp.html</guid>
      <description>The call for presentations is now open! Submit proposals by Sunday, Jun 18th, 2023 11:59 PM GMT. Please do not wait until the last minute.
Submit your talk proposal now!
We are looking for presentations about anything relating to Apache Software Foundation projects, open source governance, community, and software development.
In particular, this year we are building content tracks around the following specific topics/projects:
 AI / Machine learning API / Microservice Community CloudNative Data Storage &amp;amp; Computing DataOps Data Lake &amp;amp; Data Warehouse OLAP &amp;amp; Data Analysis Performance Engineering Incubator IoT/IIoT Messaging RPC Streaming Workflow / Data Processing Web Server / Tomcat  If your proposed presentation falls into one of these categories, please select that topic in the CFP entry form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/2024/search/search.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/search/search.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessiblity</title>
      <link>/2024/guide/accessibility.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/guide/accessibility.html</guid>
      <description>CommunityOverCode Asia strives to be a welcoming, inclusive, and accessible environment for all, regardless of ability.
Participants requiring special accommodations should provide details in their registration and/or by emailing us at ningjiang@apache.org. This information will be kept private and only be shared with individuals who need to know to secure these accommodations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI / machine learning</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/ai.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/ai.html</guid>
      <description>Machine learning (ML) is the study of computer algorithms that can improve automatically through experience and by the use of data. Machine learning algorithms build a model based on sample data, known as training data, in order to make predictions or decisions without being explicitly programmed to do so. It has a wide range of application scenarios in industry and plays an increasingly important role.
Three types of topics suitable for this sub forum are as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/cloudnative.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/cloudnative.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Software Projects practice in the cloud native environment, such as K8s, service mesh, serverless(lambda). More projects are required to deploy and run on the modern infra, and leverage them. In the Cloud Native track, we are going to share the experiences how Apache&amp;rsquo;s projects resolves this complex issue. Also, what tools and methods the ASF provided today to help the users to observe and understand the distributed system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>/2024/conduct.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/conduct.html</guid>
      <description>At the Apache Software Foundation, all online interactions are governed by the ASF Code of Conduct, while in-person events are subject to the Anti-Harassment Policy.
CommunitOverCode (formerly ApacheCon) is dedicated to providing a harassment-free experience for everyone. We do not tolerate harassment of participants in any form. Participants violating these rules may be sanctioned or expelled without a refund, at the discretion of the event organizers.
Harassment includes offensive verbal comments, deliberate intimidation, stalking, following, unwanted photography or recording, sustained disruption of talks or other events, inappropriate physical contact, and unwelcome sexual attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/community.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/community.html</guid>
      <description>Why ASF believes &amp;ldquo;Community over Code&amp;rdquo;? There is more to open source than just code contribution.
The Community track covers topics such as community governance model, growing open source project communities, diversity &amp;amp; inclusion, measuring community health, community management tools and data, project roadmaps, case studies, and any other topic around sustaining open source and open source communities.
We welcome you to share your community story with a broader audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Lake &amp; Data Warehouse</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/datalake.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/datalake.html</guid>
      <description>Data Lake and Data Warehouse are important solutions for storing and managing data, and they play a crucial role in data management, data analysis, and decision-making. In ASF, there are various projects about Data Lake and Data Warehouse, for example: Apache Hive, Apache Hudi, Apache Iceberg, Apache Paimon, Apache Cassandra, Apache HBase etc. In this topic, you will get the latest status of data lake and warehouse, best practices the companies use them in the production, and the roadmap of these projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Storage &amp; Computing</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/datastorage.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/datastorage.html</guid>
      <description>Big data is an important branch of computer science,Researches and innovations in the big data storage and computing have never stopped. Big Data is leading and changing various industries and is inseparable from our lives.
Big Data is also a very important part of ASF. ASF has so many big data storage and computing projects, such as Apache Hadoop, Apache Spark, Apache HBase, Apache Ozone, Apache CarbonData, Apache Cassandra, Apache ZooKeeper etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/dataops.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/dataops.html</guid>
      <description>Introducing the DataOps Track at ApacheCon, featuring some of the most innovative and cutting-edge projects in the Apache ecosystem. This track brings together leading experts and contributors from Apache DolphinScheduler, Apache Airflow, Apache SeaTunnel, Apache Flume, Apache Sqoop, Apache Griffin, Apache Atlas and other DataOps-related projects to explore the latest advances in data operations, automation, and orchestration. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned data professional or just getting started in the field, this track offers something for everyone, with sessions covering topics such as data pipelines, ETL, orchestration, data qulity, metadata, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/others.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/others.html</guid>
      <description>The General track of Community Over Code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incubator</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/incubator.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/incubator.html</guid>
      <description>The Apache Incubator offers valuable services to projects, referred to as &amp;ldquo;podlings,&amp;rdquo; seeking entry into the Apache Software Foundation (ASF). This conference track aims to provide insights and guidance on the incubator journey, enabling attendees to gain a deeper understanding of Apache&amp;rsquo;s governance and operational practices.
Participants will learn about the process of entering the incubator and progressing towards becoming a Top-Level Project (TLP). Additionally, this track will explore strategies for building an active and diverse open-source community, while ensuring compliance with Apache&amp;rsquo;s regulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT and IIoT</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/iot.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/iot.html</guid>
      <description>Recent years, the emerging Internet of Things (IoT) and Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT) applications show the requirements about the embedded operation system, data collection from the side, data management both on the side and the cloud, and data analysis technologies. The Apache Software Foundation provides many related projects, like Apache IoTDB, Apache Mynewt, Apache PLC4X and Apache Streampipes to meet users&#39; requirements.
This track will introduce the recent progress, some core technologies and the use experience of IoT related Apache projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynote</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/keynote.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/keynote.html</guid>
      <description>Keynote track is the main track. we invite many famous people in open source community, they will share their visions and insights about open source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messaging</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/messaging.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/messaging.html</guid>
      <description>Messaging system is used to enable communication between systems by sending messages to each other. It is used to decouple heavyweight processing, to buffer or batch work, and to smooth spiky workloads, also it can be used as the basic infrastructure for event driven and streaming systems.
In ASF, there are various projects that provide messaging services, for example: Apache Pulsar, Apache Kafka, Apache RocketMQ, Apache ActiveMQ, Apache Inlong, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monolith vs Microservice</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/api.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/api.html</guid>
      <description>Microservices have become the default choice for our technology stack, and it seems that anything other than microservices is considered outdated. However, in the past two years, doubts about microservices have started to emerge, and people have begun to miss the simplicity and directness of monolithic services, avoiding the various governance costs that come with service-oriented architecture. The industry has also witnessed the emergence of new programming frameworks that provide developers with the experience and efficiency of monolithic development while retaining the flexibility, scalability, and even certain serverless characteristic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OLAP &amp; Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/olap.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/olap.html</guid>
      <description>With the advent of the big data era, the application of data analysis and OLAP technology in enterprises is becoming more and more widespread. In order to promote communication and sharing in this field in the industry, we have set up the OLAP and Data Analysis Track. We hope to invite experts and scholars in the industry to share their research results, practical experience, and latest developments in data analysis and OLAP technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performace</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/performance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/performance.html</guid>
      <description>Why an ApacheCon Performance Engineering Track? Because many Apache projects address domains with software performance and scalability challenges (E.g. Web, Cloud, Databases, Streaming Data, Big Data, Data Analytics, Search, Geospatial, etc), while others provide performance engineering tools (E.g. benchmarking, testing, monitoring, etc) that are widely used, so the track will provide opportunities for cross-fertilization between projects of different software categories and maturity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>/2024/schedule.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/schedule.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsor</title>
      <link>/2024/sponsor.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/sponsor.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/streaming.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/streaming.html</guid>
      <description>Streaming data processing is a big deal in big data these days, businesses crave ever-more timely insights into their data, and what was once a ‘batch’ mindset is quickly being replaced with stream processing. More and more companies, small and large, are rethinking their architecture with real-time context at the forefront, and starting to build their streaming platforms with powerful open source engines such as Apache Flink, Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, Apache Pulsar, Apache Storm, Apache StreamPark (incubating), Apache Paimon (incubating) etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Server/Tomcat</title>
      <link>/2024/tracks/webserver.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2024/tracks/webserver.html</guid>
      <description>Web server plays a crucial role in internet era, and have demonstrated their strong vitality after years of development. These projects includes but not limited to Apache Tomcat / Apache Http Server / Apache Sling / Apache Traffic Server / Apache Traffic Control and etc.
In this topic, you will know the latest status of web servers, best practices the companies use them in the production, and the roadmap of these projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
