<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Over Code Asia 2025 will be held in Beijing from July 25 to 27，2025 on Community Over Code Asia 2025</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community Over Code Asia 2025 will be held in Beijing from July 25 to 27，2025 on Community Over Code Asia 2025</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Venue &#43; Travel</title>
      <link>/venue_travel/venue.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/venue_travel/venue.html</guid>
      <description>Venue This year&amp;rsquo;s conference will be held at the Convention Center of Zhongguancun National Independent Innovation Demonstration Zone (located at No. 2 Xinjian Gongmen Road, Haidian District, Beijing).
Nestled in the heart of Haidian District, Beijing, the Convention Center of Zhongguancun National Independent Innovation Demonstration Zone stands adjacent to the time-honored cultural scenic area of &amp;ldquo;Three Hills and Five Gardens&amp;rdquo; and the thriving Zhongguancun Science City. It serves as a confluence point of technology and culture, as well as a brilliant stage for innovation and exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visa Letter Request</title>
      <link>/guide/visa_letter_request.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guide/visa_letter_request.html</guid>
      <description>For those needing a visa invitation letter, please refer to the instructions on this page.
INSTRUCTIONS Before asking for a visa invitation letter, please check out the website of Chinese Visa Application Service Center for the visa application in your city.
Please pay attention to the latest visa policy of China:   240-Hour Visa-Free Transit Policy which allows people from certain countries to enjoy ten days of travel to select areas of the country without applying for a visa beforehand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a presentation slide</title>
      <link>/guide/presentation_slides_template.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guide/presentation_slides_template.html</guid>
      <description>We have a slides template.
We strongly recommend you to use the template, but if you don’t plan to use it for your entire presentation, please use the title slide at least.
 If you use your own template, please set your slide size ratio as 16:9. Do not include any offensive or sexualized references. This would be a violation of the Code of Conduct.  Talks are 30 minutes long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convince Your Boss</title>
      <link>/guide/code_of_conduct.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guide/code_of_conduct.html</guid>
      <description>At the Apache Software Foundation, all online interactions are governed by the ASF Code of Conduct, while in-person events are subject to the Anti-Harassment Policy.
Community Over Code (formerly ApacheCon) is dedicated to providing a harassment-free experience for everyone. We do not tolerate harassment of participants in any form. Participants violating these rules may be sanctioned or expelled without a refund, at the discretion of the event organizers.
Harassment includes offensive verbal comments, deliberate intimidation, stalking, following, unwanted photography or recording, sustained disruption of talks or other events, inappropriate physical contact, and unwelcome sexual attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convince Your Boss</title>
      <link>/guide/convince_your_boss.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guide/convince_your_boss.html</guid>
      <description>Want to attend but not sure how to bring it up with your boss? We’ve created this sample email to help you explain why it’s important to attend Community Over Code Asia 2025. Feel free to use the full letter or pieces that work for you. See you in Beijing!
Download Template </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/cfp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cfp.html</guid>
      <description>The call for presentations is now open! Submit proposals by Sunday, Jun 18th, 2023 11:59 PM GMT. Please do not wait until the last minute.
Submit your talk proposal now!
We are looking for presentations about anything relating to Apache Software Foundation projects, open source governance, community, and software development.
In particular, this year we are building content tracks around the following specific topics/projects:
 AI / Machine learning API / Microservice Community CloudNative Data Storage &amp;amp; Computing DataOps Data Lake &amp;amp; Data Warehouse OLAP &amp;amp; Data Analysis Performance Engineering Incubator IoT/IIoT Messaging RPC Streaming Workflow / Data Processing Web Server / Tomcat  If your proposed presentation falls into one of these categories, please select that topic in the CFP entry form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/search/search.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/search/search.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessiblity</title>
      <link>/guide/accessibility.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guide/accessibility.html</guid>
      <description>Community Over Code Asia strives to be a welcoming, inclusive, and accessible environment for all, regardless of ability.
Participants requiring special accommodations should provide details in their registration and/or by emailing us at ningjiang@apache.org. This information will be kept private and only be shared with individuals who need to know to secure these accommodations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI</title>
      <link>/tracks/ai.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/ai.html</guid>
      <description>The AI Sub-forum is a professional exchange platform focusing on the integration of artificial intelligence (AI) technology and Apache open-source projects. This sub-forum aims to bring together developers, researchers, and industry users from around the world to explore the application and development of AI technology in the open-source ecosystem, showcase cutting-edge technologies, share practical experience, and promote the implementation of open-source AI solutions across various industries. Topics suitable for this sub-forum include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Travel</title>
      <link>/venue_travel/travel.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/venue_travel/travel.html</guid>
      <description>Conference Hotel Park Plaza Beijing Science Park Hotel is 4.6km from the venue, approximately 20 minutes by taxi. Special conference rates (including breakfast):
   Room Type King Bed Twin Bed     Superior Room 618 698   Deluxe Room 658 738   Business Room 758 838   Executive Room 838 938    Booking Instructions: Call Park Plaza Beijing Science Park Hotel and mention “COC Asia” for special rates Reservation Department: 010-82356699 ext.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Native</title>
      <link>/tracks/cloudnative.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/cloudnative.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Software Projects practice in the cloud native environment, such as K8s, service mesh, serverless(lambda). More projects are required to deploy and run on the modern infra, and leverage them. In the Cloud Native track, we are going to share the experiences how Apache’s projects resolves this complex issue. Also, what tools and methods the ASF provided today to help the users to observe and understand the distributed system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code, Culture, and Policy: Shaping Asia’s Open Source Future in a Global Context</title>
      <link>/sessions/keynote-889680.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sessions/keynote-889680.html</guid>
      <description>As open source becomes vital for global innovation, the impact of policymaking on its growth is crucial. This keynote explores the unique challenges and opportunities for Asia&amp;rsquo;s open source ecosystem, contrasting it with Western legislative frameworks like the U.S. CHIPS Act and Europe’s Cyber Resilience Act (CRA). While these policies aim to enhance technological leadership, Asia’s approach—shaped by its cultural and geopolitical context—presents a distinct narrative.
With initiatives like China’s 14th Five-Year Plan promoting indigenous technologies, Taiwan’s g0v community driving civic tech innovation, and India&amp;rsquo;s policy on adoption of OSS in e-Governance, Asia is forging its path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>/tracks/community.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/community.html</guid>
      <description>Why ASF believes &amp;ldquo;Community over Code&amp;rdquo;? There is more to open source than just code contribution.
The Community track covers topics such as community governance model, growing open source project communities, diversity &amp;amp; inclusion, measuring community health, community management tools and data, project roadmaps, case studies, and any other topic around sustaining open source and open source communities.
We welcome you to share your community story with a broader audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Lake &amp; Data Warehouse</title>
      <link>/tracks/datalake.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/datalake.html</guid>
      <description>Data Lake and Data Warehouse are important solutions for storing and managing data, and they play a crucial role in data management, data analysis, and decision-making. In ASF, there are various projects about Data Lake and Data Warehouse, for example: Apache Hive, Apache Hudi, Apache Iceberg, Apache Paimon, Apache Cassandra, Apache HBase etc. In this topic, you will get the latest status of data lake and warehouse, best practices the companies use them in the production, and the roadmap of these projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Storage &amp; Computing</title>
      <link>/tracks/datastorage.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/datastorage.html</guid>
      <description>Big data is an important branch of computer science,Researches and innovations in the big data storage and computing have never stopped. Big Data is leading and changing various industries and is inseparable from our lives.
Big Data is also a very important part of ASF. ASF has so many big data storage and computing projects, such as Apache Hadoop, Apache Spark, Apache HBase, Apache Ozone, Apache CarbonData, Apache Cassandra, Apache ZooKeeper etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataOps</title>
      <link>/tracks/dataops.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/dataops.html</guid>
      <description>Featuring some of the most innovative and cutting-edge projects in the Apache ecosystem. This track brings together leading experts and contributors from Apache DolphinScheduler, Apache Airflow, Apache SeaTunnel, Apache Flume, Apache Sqoop, Apache Griffin, Apache Atlas and other DataOps-related projects to explore the latest advances in data operations, automation, and orchestration. Whether you’re a seasoned data professional or just getting started in the field, this track offers something for everyone, with sessions covering topics such as data pipelines, ETL, orchestration, data qulity, metadata, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General</title>
      <link>/tracks/general.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/general.html</guid>
      <description>The General track of Community Over Code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Keep Your Open Source Project Going After the Hype Dies Down</title>
      <link>/sessions/keynote-915301.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sessions/keynote-915301.html</guid>
      <description>This session will explain the Gartner Hype Cycle and how it applies to open source software projects. I&amp;rsquo;ll share insight into the role that both word-of-mouth and social media play in getting developers to contribute to your open source project. We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to get attention and how to adapt as that attention inevitably fades.
freeCodeCamp&amp;rsquo;s open source project has over 400,000 stars on GitHub and more than 50,000 codebase contributions over the past 10 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incubator</title>
      <link>/tracks/incubator.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/incubator.html</guid>
      <description>The Apache Incubator offers valuable services to projects, referred to as &amp;ldquo;podlings,&amp;rdquo; seeking entry into the Apache Software Foundation (ASF). This conference track aims to provide insights and guidance on the incubator journey, enabling attendees to gain a deeper understanding of Apache&amp;rsquo;s governance and operational practices.
Participants will learn about the process of entering the incubator and progressing towards becoming a Top-Level Project (TLP). Additionally, this track will explore strategies for building an active and diverse open-source community, while ensuring compliance with Apache&amp;rsquo;s regulations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Apache Community from China Open Source Annual Report</title>
      <link>/sessions/keynote-914074.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sessions/keynote-914074.html</guid>
      <description>With the rapid development of the global open-source ecosystem, the influence of China&amp;rsquo;s open-source community on the international stage has continued to grow. This report is based on data analysis from the China Open Source Annual Report, focusing on the participation, technical contributions, and development trends of the Apache open-source community in China. It aims to reveal the community&amp;rsquo;s role and challenges within the global open-source ecosystem.
Speakers: 
Wei Wang: Professor of East China Normal University</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT and IIoT</title>
      <link>/tracks/iot.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/iot.html</guid>
      <description>The loT Track will be a gathering of innovativeminds and industry experts in the loT field. This track focuses on theatest trends,technologies, and applications in the lnternet ofThings. During the event, attendees will have the opportunity toexplore a wide range of topics, including loT device data collectingdata storage, data analytics, security, and the loT solutions.
In order to better realize the core needs of the IoT industry such as device communication, data management, and edge-cloud collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynote</title>
      <link>/tracks/keynote.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/keynote.html</guid>
      <description>Keynote track is the main track. we invite many famous people in open source community, they will share their visions and insights about open source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messaging</title>
      <link>/tracks/messaging.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/messaging.html</guid>
      <description>With the large-scale landing of serverless, IoT and real-time data technology, event-driven architecture and event streaming technology have been more widely applied, making message queue become more and more important infrastructure. Today, a number of excellent messaging projects have emerged in the Apache ecosystem, including Apache Pulsar, Apache Kafka, Apache RocketMQ, Apache ActiveMQ, Apache Inlong, etc, facing new technological trends, each messaging project is also continuing to evolve.
In this topic, you will learn how different messaging systems make the best technical evolution direction based on their own architectural characteristics, including storage and computing separation, serverless, messaging-streaming integration,and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservice</title>
      <link>/tracks/microservice.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/microservice.html</guid>
      <description>Whether in the era of Cloud Native or AI-led transformation today, microservices remain the cornerstone of underlying systems, helping us build resilient and scalable distributed systems. Join us as we uncover:
  High-Performance RPC Frameworks – Learn how projects like Apache Dubbo, Apache Thrift, and Apache bRPC are redefining service-to-service communication with speed, efficiency, and interoperability.
  AI-Driven Microservices – Discover how AI and ML are revolutionizing service orchestration, anomaly detection, and autonomous scaling in microservice ecosystems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observability</title>
      <link>/tracks/observability.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/observability.html</guid>
      <description>As an essential technical capability in the cloud-native era, observability—the ability to analyze and interpret a system&amp;rsquo;s operational state—has gained increasing importance. Especially in today&amp;rsquo;s widespread adoption of distributed environments, observability platforms serve as the cornerstone for ensuring software system stability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OLAP &amp; Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/tracks/olap.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/olap.html</guid>
      <description>With the advent of the big data era, the application of data analysis and OLAP technology in enterprises is becoming more and more widespread. In order to promote communication and sharing in this field in the industry, we have set up the OLAP and Data Analysis Track. We hope to invite experts and scholars in the industry to share their research results, practical experience, and latest developments in data analysis and OLAP technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rising to the Challenges in Security</title>
      <link>/sessions/keynote-914928.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sessions/keynote-914928.html</guid>
      <description>This talk discusses the current state of security in open source software, and in particular, how the ASF is responding to the growing threat. The ASF started with the first project: a web server running on an open source operating system. Since then, the organization has built hundreds of communities based on principles of openness, collaboration, and public good. Open source is now considered to be the principal component of most commercial software projects, accounting for some 90% of all commercial code, with an estimated value of USD $8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust</title>
      <link>/tracks/rust.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/rust.html</guid>
      <description>The Rust ecosystem is flourishing. Many ASF projects now offer Rust SDKs, and several new ASF projects are primarily written in Rust, such as Apache OpenDAL and Apache HoraeDB (Incubating), among others.
The Rust Track aims to share the evolution of Rust projects and integrations within the ASF and broader open-source ecosystem. It will demonstrate how ASF projects provide excellent Rust implementations and illustrate how the incubator helps Rust projects develop healthy communities under the guidance of The Apache Way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>/schedule.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/schedule.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsor</title>
      <link>/sponsor.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sponsor.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming</title>
      <link>/tracks/streaming.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/streaming.html</guid>
      <description>Streaming data processing is a big deal in big data these days, businesses crave ever-more timely insights into their data, and what was once a ‘batch’ mindset is quickly being replaced with stream processing. More and more companies, small and large, are rethinking their architecture with real-time context at the forefront, and starting to build their streaming platforms with powerful open source engines such as Apache Flink, Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, Apache Pulsar, Apache Storm, Apache StreamPark (incubating), Apache Paimon (incubating) etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms &amp; Conditions</title>
      <link>/guide/terms.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guide/terms.html</guid>
      <description>Refund Policy If you must cancel for any reason please notify us via email at vivian@segmentfault.com. Refunds will only be issued for cancellations received 14 days prior to the first day of the event and may take up to 14 days to process. Please note that all refunds are subject to a 3% processing fee. You can cancel or modify your registration from your confirmation email.
Photo &amp;amp; Video Release I hereby consent to the photographing of myself and the recording of my voice and the use of these photographs and/or recordings singularly or in conjunction with other photographs and/or recordings for advertising, publicity, commercial or other business purposes for The Apache Software Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Application &amp; Framework</title>
      <link>/tracks/webserver.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tracks/webserver.html</guid>
      <description>With the growing demands of modern web applications, building efficient, scalable, and secure web systems has become a core objective of technological development.
Within the Apache ecosystem, numerous outstanding projects have emerged, ranging from classic web servers (such as Tomcat, HTTP Server) to essential development tools (like Apache Commons, FreeMarker, Echarts), as well as frameworks specializing in enterprise-level integration and security (e.g., Camel, Shiro). These projects play critical roles in modern web architectures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
