<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sessions on Community Over Code Asia 2025</title>
    <link>/sessions.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sessions on Community Over Code Asia 2025</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code, Culture, and Policy: Shaping Asia’s Open Source Future in a Global Context</title>
      <link>/sessions/keynote-889680.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sessions/keynote-889680.html</guid>
      <description>As open source becomes vital for global innovation, the impact of policymaking on its growth is crucial. This keynote explores the unique challenges and opportunities for Asia&amp;rsquo;s open source ecosystem, contrasting it with Western legislative frameworks like the U.S. CHIPS Act and Europe’s Cyber Resilience Act (CRA). While these policies aim to enhance technological leadership, Asia’s approach—shaped by its cultural and geopolitical context—presents a distinct narrative.
With initiatives like China’s 14th Five-Year Plan promoting indigenous technologies, Taiwan’s g0v community driving civic tech innovation, and India&amp;rsquo;s policy on adoption of OSS in e-Governance, Asia is forging its path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Keep Your Open Source Project Going After the Hype Dies Down</title>
      <link>/sessions/keynote-915301.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sessions/keynote-915301.html</guid>
      <description>This session will explain the Gartner Hype Cycle and how it applies to open source software projects. I&amp;rsquo;ll share insight into the role that both word-of-mouth and social media play in getting developers to contribute to your open source project. We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to get attention and how to adapt as that attention inevitably fades.
freeCodeCamp&amp;rsquo;s open source project has over 400,000 stars on GitHub and more than 50,000 codebase contributions over the past 10 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Apache Community from China Open Source Annual Report</title>
      <link>/sessions/keynote-914074.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sessions/keynote-914074.html</guid>
      <description>With the rapid development of the global open-source ecosystem, the influence of China&amp;rsquo;s open-source community on the international stage has continued to grow. This report is based on data analysis from the China Open Source Annual Report, focusing on the participation, technical contributions, and development trends of the Apache open-source community in China. It aims to reveal the community&amp;rsquo;s role and challenges within the global open-source ecosystem.
Speakers: 
Wei Wang: Professor of East China Normal University</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rising to the Challenges in Security</title>
      <link>/sessions/keynote-914928.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sessions/keynote-914928.html</guid>
      <description>This talk discusses the current state of security in open source software, and in particular, how the ASF is responding to the growing threat. The ASF started with the first project: a web server running on an open source operating system. Since then, the organization has built hundreds of communities based on principles of openness, collaboration, and public good. Open source is now considered to be the principal component of most commercial software projects, accounting for some 90% of all commercial code, with an estimated value of USD $8.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
